<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004857">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Andrew Jackson James</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004857">
                    <persName>
                      Andrew Jackson James
                        (Frankfort attorney and Attorney General of Kentucky)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1817-06-04"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Frankfort attorney and Attorney General of Kentucky. Pulaski County native. Married Marry A. Beatie James in 1841. Father of John James, Daniel James, Clara James, Samuel James, and Emma James. Pulaski County Representative in 1855. Attorney General of Kentucky from 1859 to 1863. Held ten slaves in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>: <em>The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</em> (Cincinnati, OH: J. M. Armstrong and Company, 1878), p. 314. Clarence E. Walker, <em>Proceedings of the Twelfth Annual Meeting of the Kentucky State Bar Association, Held in Olympian Springs, Ky., July 9, 10 and 11, 1913</em> (Louisville, KY: Westerfield-Bonte Company, 1913), p. 177-176. C. E. James, <em>A Short History of Franklin County, Kentucky, Prepared in Compliance with the Suggestion of the Resolution of Congress in Regard to the Celebration of the Centennial Anniversary, and Read at Sunday-school Picnic at Lake Park, Near Frankfort, Kentucky on the Fourth of July, 1876</em> (Frankfort, KY: George A. Lewis, 1881), p. 10. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Pulaski County, Somerset, p. 1. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Pulaski County, Somerset. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 75. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 10. Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 12.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
