<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006355">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Archibald C. Cox</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006355">
                    <persName>
                      Archibald C. Cox
                        (Green County sheriff and farmer)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="c1798"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Green County, Kentucky sheriff and farmer. Virginia native. Married Sally W. Howe Cox in 1822. Married Harriet W. Buckner Cox. Father of John H. Cox, Charles Cox. Held eight slaves in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>KYR-0001-004-1972. Jordan Dodd, <em>Kentucky Marriages, 1802-1850</em>, Ancestry, Green County, 1822. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District 2, p. 126. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District 2, p. 217. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg and Alendale, District 1, p. 12. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District 1, p. 4. Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg, p. 2. Green County Court Clerk, <em>Will Book 4</em>, Ancestry, p. 63-64. <em>Kentucky Vital Statistics Original Death Certificates (1911-1955)</em>, Ancestry, 1913, Taylor County, file no. 11518.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
