<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006168">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Horatio Wright</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006168">
                    <persName>
                      Horatio Wright
                        (Union General )
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1820-03-06"></birth>
                      <death when="1889-07-02"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born in Clinton, Connecticut March 6, 1820. Graduated from the U.S. Military Academy in 1842. Assistant Professor of Engineering at West Point from 1842-1884. Appointed a Brigadier General of Volunteers in September 1861, and Major General of Volunteers in July 1862. During the Civil War, he served Chief engineer of Heintzelman&#39;s Division at the battle of Bull Run, and in the Port Royal expedition, he commanded a Brigade. In February 1862, he was in the expedition that captured Fernandina, Florida, and commanded a Division in the attack on Secessionville, South Carolina in June 1862. In July he was assigned to the Department of the Ohio, and commanded the 1st Division, VI Corps, in the Army of the Potomac at Gettysburg. After General Sedgwick&#39;s death, he was in command of the VI Corps, which he led in the Richmond campaign until July 1864. In August to December, he was engaged in the Shenandoah campaign. He was wounded in the battle of Cedar Creek, and was in final military operations which ended with the surrender of Lee. After the Civil War he was military governor of Texas until 1866 when he resumed his practice of civil engineering. Breveted Major General, US Army, in March 1865. Died at Washington, DC, July 2, 1899.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>&quot;Horatio Gouverneuer Wright, Major General, United States Army” *Arlington National Cemetery Website’ http://www.arlingtoncemetery.net/hgwright.htm</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
