<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004393">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert Young Bush</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004393">
                    <persName>
                      Robert Young Bush
                        (Hancock County lawyer and common schools commissioner)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1826-06-30"></birth>
                      <death when="1900-01-26"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Lived in Hancock County, Kentucky in 1861. Married to Ann Millian Stone Bush. Worked as an attorney in Hancock County in 1854 and 1856, serving as county attorney in 1856. Served as a county commissioner of the Hancock County common schools in 1854, 1861, and 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>John Livingston, <em>Livingston&#39;s Law Register: A Guide for Every Man of Business, and Hand-book of Useful Knowledge</em> (New York: Office of the Monthly Law Magazeine, 1854), 109; John Livingston, <em>Livingston&#39;s Law Register: Containing a Complete List of Lawyers in the United States</em> (New York: Davies and Roberts, 1856), 133 and 303; &quot;Report of the Superintendent Public Instruction to the Governor of Kentucky, for the Year 1854,&quot; <em>Kentucky Public Documents: Legislative Document, No. 2</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1855), 104; &quot;Annual Report of the Superintendent of Public Instruction of Kentucky, for the School Year Ending December 31, 1861,&quot; (Frankfort, Ky.: Yeoman Office, Jno. B. Major, State Printer, 1862), 63 and 135; &quot;Annual Report of the Superintendent of Public Instruction of Kentucky, for the School Year Ending December 31, 1863,&quot; (Frankfort, Ky.: Commonwealth Office, Wm. E. Hughes, State Printer, 1864), 65; &quot;Robert Young Bush,&quot; (https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=89300171) (accessed on April 12, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
