<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008248">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Henry Wolfe</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008248">
                    <persName>
                      John Henry Wolfe
                        (Scott County, KY, German-born grocer and Confederate captain)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1825"></birth>
                      <death when="1897"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Residence: Georgetown, Scott County, Kentucky. A Bremen, Germany-born grocer. Emigrated to the U.S. at age 16. Came to Georgetown, Kentucky in 1840 and remained there the rest of his life. In the grocery business until the Civil War broke out. Then he enlisted in General John H. Morgan&#39;s forces, in July 1862. In September 1862 he returned to Georgetown and raised a company, of which he was elected captain. His command became Company D, 3rd Kentucky Cavalry, under Colonel Gano. Served in the Ohio and Indiana raids and was captured at Middleport, Ohio. Released through a prisoner exchange seven months later. Married Elizabeth Zeysing.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Find A Grave, Entry for Capt John Henry Wolfe (1825-1897), Find A Grave Memorial #  102041855, Georgetown Cemetery, Georgetown, Scott County, Kentucky, https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GSln=wolfe&amp;GSbyrel=all&amp;GSdyrel=all&amp;GSst=19&amp;GScnty=1093&amp;GScntry=4&amp;GSob=n&amp;GRid=102041855&amp;df=all&amp; (accessed 14 Aug 2017).</p>

<p>Perrin, William Henry, ed., &quot;History of Bourbon, Scott, Harrison and Nicholas Counties, Kentucky* (Chicago: O.L. Baskin &amp; Co., 1882), 620, accessed http://www.usbiographies.org/biographies/read.php?465,2233</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
