<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000846">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Eli Metcalfe Bruce</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000846">
                    <persName>
                      Eli Metcalfe Bruce
                        (Representative (Confederate))
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1828-02-22"></birth>
                      <death when="1866-12-15"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky merchant, businessman, soldier, and politician. Received a common education. Married to Elizabeth Sarah “Sallie” Withers Bruce. Father of Mattie Withers Bruce Reynolds, George Stubblefield Bruce, and Charles Albert Withers Bruce. Worked as a clerk at a dry good store in Maysville, Kentucky in 1847. Worked in the pork-packing industry in the Cincinnati, Ohio with his uncle John S. Morgan. Owned several pork and beef packing plants along the Wabash, Missouri, and Mississippi rivers—based in St. Louis, Missouri and Chattanooga, Tennessee. Established and owned an iron furnace operation with his uncle Henry Bruce, Jr. in Terra Haute, Indiana in 1854. Served as a staff officer for John C. Breckinridge in the Confederate State Army during the Civil War. Served as a member of the Council of Ten in the Provisional Government of Kentucky. Served the Ninth Congressional District as a member of the Second Confederate Congress in the House of Representatives from 1862 to 1865. Appointed by Confederate Secretary of War James E. Seddon as acting commissary general of the Confederate States of America from January 30, 1865 to the end of the war. Moved to New York City, New York.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Ezra J. Warner and W. Buck Yearns, <em>Biographical Register of the Confederate Congress</em> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1975), 36; Lewis Collins and Richard Collins, <em>History of Kentucky</em>, vol. 1 (Collins &amp; Company, 1882), 353; “Bruce, Eli Metcalf,” <em>The Encyclopedia of Northern Kentucky</em>, ed. Paul A. Tenkotte and James C. Claypool (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2015), 125; Bruce Family Papers, Eva G. Farris Special Collections, W. Frank Steely Library, Northern Kentucky University, (https://steelyarchives.nku.edu/specialcollections/alphabeticallist/bruce.html) (accessed January 19, 2017); “Eli Metcalfe Bruce,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=10043) (accessed January 19, 2017); “Death of Eli M. Bruce,” <em>Daily Courier</em> (Louisville, Ky.), December 17, 1866; “The Late E. M. Bruce,” <em>Daily Courier</em> (Louisville, Ky.), December 25, 1866; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Missouri, St. Louis County, 5th Ward City of St. Louis, p. 212.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
