<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004133">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Manley Newman</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004133">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas Manley Newman
                        (Hancock County farmer and postmaster)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1805-01-15"></birth>
                      <death when="1867-12-23"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky farmer and postmaster. Lived in Hancock County, Kentucky in 1860. Married to Nancy Newman. Father of Albert H. Newman. Owned three enslaved persons in 1850 and five in 1860. Served as postmaster of of Hawesville, Kentucky from June 1859 to November 1860. Member of the Masonic Order at Hancock Lodge, No. 115 in Hawesville, Kentucky.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971</em>, NARA Microfilm Publication, M841, Records of the Post Office Department, Record Group Number 28, accessed on ancestry.com (Washington, D.C.: National Archives) (accessed on March 22, 2017); <em>Proceedings of the Grand Lodge of kentucky, at a Grand Annual Communication, in the City of Louisville, Commencing on Monday, the 21st Day of October, 1867</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: Frankfort Commonwealth, 1867), 111-112; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County, Hawesville, p. 112; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County, Hawesville, p. 10; &quot;Thomas Manley Newman,&quot; (https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=89571776&amp;ref=acom) (accessed on April 10, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
