<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000832">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Willis Benson Machen</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000832">
                    <persName>
                      Willis Benson Machen
                        (Representative (Confederate))
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1810-04-10"></birth>
                      <death when="1893-09-29"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney, farmer, manufacturer, and politician. Attended Cumberland College in Princeton, Kentucky. Pursued farming and manufactured iron near Eddyville, Kentucky. Married thrice, first Margaret Aurelia Lyon Machen, a second time to Eliza W. Dobbins Machen, and a third time to Victoria Theresa Mims Machen. Father of Mary J. Machen, Henry L. Machen, Edward Chittenden Machen, Willis B. Machen, John S. Machen, Mary E. Machen, Elizabeth Machen, Minerva Buckner Machen Sayre, Frank Machen, Charles B. Machen, and Willis B. Machen. Served as a member of the 1849 Kentucky Constitutional Convention from Lyon County, Kentucky. Served as a member of the Kentucky Senate in 1854. Served as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1856 to 1860. Served as a member of the Council of Ten in the Provisional Government of Kentucky. Served the First Kentucky District as a member of the First and Second Confederate Congresses from 1862 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Machen, Willis Benson,” http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=M000012 (accessed January 11, 2017); Charles Lanman, Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 313; Ezra J. Warner and W. Buck Yearns, Biographical Register of the Confederate Congress (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1975),159-160; “Willis Benson Machen,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=7932701) (accessed January 11, 2017); “Death a Welcome Relief: Ex-United States Senator Willis B. Machen Expires In the Hopkinsville Asylum,” <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), September 30, 1893; “Machen, Willis Benson,” <em>The Kentucky Encyclopedia</em>, ed. John E. Kleber (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 1992), 598; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Caldwell County, The Second District; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Lyon County, Eddyville, p. 107; Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Lyon County, District No 1, p. 7.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
