<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006585">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Ethan Allen Hitchcock</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006585">
                    <persName>
                      Ethan Allen Hitchcock
                        (Union POW Commissioner)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1798-05-18"></birth>
                      <death when="1870-08-05"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Vermont soldier. Vergennes, Vermont, native. Grandson of Ethan Allen. Graduated from the United States Military Academy in West Point, New York, in 1817. Commissioned Captain in the 1st United States Infantry Regiment in 1824. Inspector General on the staff of Winfield Scott during the Mexican-American War. Commissioned Colonel of the 2nd United States Infantry Regiment in 1851. Resigned from the United States Army in 1855. St. Louis, Missouri, resident. Commissioned Major General of Volunteers in the United States Army in 1862. Detailed on service as commissioner for the exchange of prisoners. Appointed Commissary General of Prisoners in November 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Ezra J. Warner, <em>Generals in Blue: Lives of the Union Commanders</em> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press), 230-31.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
