<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00005701">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Samuel M. Boone</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00005701">
                    <persName>
                      Samuel M. Boone
                        (Danvile Attorney, 1st Regiment Kentucky Cavalry)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1837"></birth>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born in 1837 in Kentucky. Danville Attorney. Married to Mary Boone. Children included G.C., Fannie, Lucinda, Lou W., Daniel, W.L., Samuel, ad Gilby K. Enlisted in First Kentucky Cavalry Regiment on August 1, 1861, as 2nd Lieutenant. Promoted to Captain, December 2, 1862. Resigned August 12, 1863. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Sergeant E. Tarrant, <em>The Wild Riders of the First Kentucky Cavalry : a History of the Regiment, in the Great War of the Rebellion, 1861-1865 : Pathetic Scenes, Amusing Incidents, and Thrilling Episodes, a Regimental Roster, Prison Life, Adventures, and Escapes</em> (New York: New York Public Library, 1894), p. 418; <em>Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States (1880)</em>, Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, Danville, ED 13, sheet 415C, NARA microfilm publication T9 (Washington D.C.: National Archives and Records Administration, n.d.), roll 0404; FHL microfilm 1,254,404.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
