<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000851">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Milton Elliott</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000851">
                    <persName>
                      John Milton Elliott
                        (Representative (Confederate))
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1820-05-20"></birth>
                      <death when="1879-03-26"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney, politician, and jurist. Graduated at Emory and Henry College in 1841. Studied law and admitted to the bar in 1843. Practiced law in Prestonsburg, Kentucky. Married to Sarah Janes Smith Elliott. Member of the Democratic Party. Owned three enslaved persons in 1860. Served as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives in 1847 and 1861. Served the Sixth Congressional District of Kentucky as a member of the United States House of Representative from 1853 to 1859. Indicted for treason in 1861. Served as a private in the 5th Kentucky Infantry of the Confederates States Army in 1862. Served as a delegate to the Provisional Confederate Congress in 1862. Served the Twelfth Congressional District as a member of the First and Second Confederate Congresses in the House of Representatives from 1862 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Ezra J. Warner and W. Buck Yearns, <em>Biographical Register of the Confederate Congress</em> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1975), 82-83; <em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Elliott, John Milton,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=E000125) (accessed January 23, 2017); Lewis Collins and Richard Collins, <em>History of Kentucky</em>, vol. 1 (Collins &amp; Company, 1882), 353; <em>The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</em>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 38-39; H. Levin, <em>The Lawyers and Lawmakers of Kentucky</em> (Chicago: The Lewis Publishing Company, 1897), 89-90; “Elliott, John Milton,” <em>The Kentucky Encyclopedia</em>, ed. John E. Kleber (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 1992), 291-292; “John Milton Elliott,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=7644549) (accessed January 23, 2017); “Buford’s Appeal: A Judge of Kentucky’s Highest Court Shot Down in the Capital,” <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), March 27, 1879; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Floyd County, District No 1, p. 6.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
