<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006279">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John J Pettus</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006279">
                    <persName>
                      John J Pettus
                        (Mississippi Governor)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1813-09-09"></birth>
                      <death when="1867-01-28"></death>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born on October 9, 1813 in Wilson County, Tennessee. Moved to Mississippi in 1835 to study law. He opened a law practice in the early 1840&#39;s in Scooba, Mississippi. Throughout his career as a lawyer and politician, Pettus was a very active pro-secessionist. Pettus was elected to the Mississippi House of Representatives in 1844. He was then elected to the Mississippi State Senate in 1848. Pettus served a brief stent of less than a week as governor in 1854 when Governor Henry Foote resigned. He returned to the Governorship in 1859 when he was elected governor on a platform of secession and the formation of a Southern Confederacy. A year later, Governor Pettus called for the Mississippi Secession Convention to debate the issues of secession. Mississippi Seceded from the Union on January 9, 1861. Later that same year Pettus was elected to his second term as governor. After the completion of his second term, he was commissioned as a colonel in the state militia. John Pettus died of pneumonia on January 28, 1867 in Jefferson County, Arkansas. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Robert W. Dubay, <em>John Jones Pettus, Mississippi Fire-eater: His Life and Times, 1813-1867</em> (Jackson: University Press of Mississippi, 1975)24, 55; Ben Wynne, <em>Mississippi&#39;s Civil War: A Narrative History</em> (Macon: Mercer University Press, 2006), 18, 20; John J Pettus, &quot;Inagural Address&quot; (speech, Mississippi, 1859), New York University Library, https://aleph.library.nyu.edu/F/86H2H9NKEILGM6R3EMUCIVGGXCN6P43L1G8HF7L7G341GCESYB-00858?func=direct&amp;amp=&amp;amp=&amp;local<em>base=PRIMOCOMMON&amp;doc</em>number=001323037&amp;pds_handle=GUEST.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
