<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000853">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Philip Burton Thompson, Sr.</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000853">
                    <persName>
                      Philip Burton Thompson, Sr.
                        (Provisional Government of Kentucky)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1821-01-08"></birth>
                      <death when="1908-11-28"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney, soldier, and politician. Admitted to the bar and practiced law in Mercer County, Kentucky. Married twice, first to Martha Adelaide Montgomery Thompson and a second time to Almedia Mundy Thompson. Father of Daviess/Davis M. Thompson, Philip “Little Phil” Burton Thompson, Jr., and John Burton Thompson. Member of the Whig Party. Served as a captain in the Second Regiment Kentucky Foot Volunteers in the Mexican War from 1846 to 1847. Served as a member of the Council of Ten in the Provisional Government of Kentucky.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Lewis Collins and Richard Collins, <em>History of Kentucky</em>, vol. 1 (Collins &amp; Company, 1882), 353; John J. McAfee, <em>Kentucky Politicians: Sketches of Representative Corncrackers and other Miscellany</em> (Louisville: Press of the Courier-Journal Job Printing Company, 1886), 156-157; “Colonel Phillip Burton Thompson, Sr ,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=126486353) (accessed January 25, 2017); “Full of Years Noted Man Dies: Col. Phil B. Thompson, Sr., Is No More,” <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), November 29, 1908; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District No 1; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, p. 2; Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, p. 6.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
