<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004598">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Silas W. Hunt</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004598">
                    <persName>
                      Silas W. Hunt
                        (Henry County survery, farmer, and soldier)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="c1804"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky surveyor, farmer, and soldier. Lived in Henry County, Kentucky in 1860. Married to Lucinda Hunt. Father of A. S. Hunt, Elizabeth Hunt, Philip P. Hunt, Mathew W. Hunt, Nicholas O. Hunt, Rheuben P. Hunt, and John Allen Hunt. Owned seven enslaved persons in 1850 and hired out two enslaved person in 1860. Worked as a Henry County surveyor in 1842, 1848, and 1850. Worked as a Henry County farmer in 1860. Served a lieutenant colonel in a unit of the Kentucky State Guard in 1862. A founding member of the Kentucky River Navigation Company in 1865. Member of the Masonic Order at Faithful Friend Lodge, No. 313 in Lockport, Kentucky.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Proceedings of the Grand Lodge of Kentucky, at a Grand Annual Communication, in the City of Louisville, Commencing on Monday, the 21st Day of October, 1867</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: Frankfort Commonwealth, 1867), 232; &quot;An Act to Establish a State Road from the Ohio River to Albany in Clinton County, and for other purposes,&quot; <em>Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky: Passed at December Session, 1841</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1842), 67-68; &quot;An Act for the benefit of the Surveyors of Henry and Lewis Counties,&quot; <em>Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky: Passed at December Session, 1847</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: A. G. Hodges &amp; Co–State Printer, 1848), 259-260; &quot;An Act to incorporate the Kentucky River Navigation Company,&quot;  <em>Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky: Passed at December Session</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: George D. Prentice, State Printer, 1865), 96-100; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henry County, District No. 1; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Henry County, District No. 1; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henry County, Subdivision No. 1, p. 60; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Henry County, Subdivision No. 1, p. 5; </p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
