<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000852">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James P. Bates</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000852">
                    <persName>
                      James P. Bates
                        (Provisional Government of Kentucky)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="c1810"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney and politician. Practiced law in Barren County, Kentucky and Bowling Green, Kentucky. Married to Harriet Bates. Father of Virginia Bates, William Bates, James Bates, John Bates, George Bates, Edward Bates, and Frank Bates. Member of the Jacksonian Democratic Party and the Democratic Party. Canvassed for Stephen A. Douglas in the 1860 presidential election. Served as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives in 1836 for several terms. Served as a member of the Council of Ten in the Provisional Government of Kentucky. Returned to Bowling Green, Kentucky to practice law.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Lewis Collins and Richard Collins, <em>History of Kentucky</em>, vol. 1 (Collins &amp; Company, 1882), 353; H. Levin, <em>The Lawyers and Lawmakers of Kentucky</em> (Chicago: The Lewis Publishing Company, 1897), 468; “Douglas Sentiments,” <em>Daily Courier</em> (Louisville, Ky.), October 19, 1860; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Barren County; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Barren County, District No 2, p. 157; Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, Bowling Green Precinct, p. 17.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
