<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003379">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Albert G. Waggener</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003379">
                    <persName>
                      Albert G. Waggener
                        (Cumberland County sheriff)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="c1801"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Cumberland County sheriff and farmer. Virginia native. Married Luckie V. Waggener. Father of Lewis A. Waggener, Emily Waggener, Martha Waggener, Harriet Waggener, and James Waggener. Held eight slaves in 1860. Cumberland County sheriff from c1845 to 1860 and 1864. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>KYR-0001-004-1309. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Cumberland County, Burkesville, p. 280. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Cumberland County, District 2, p. 76. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Cumberland County, District 2, p. 11. <em>Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky: Passed at December Session, 1845 (Frankfort, KY: A. G. Hodges, 1846), chapter 67, section 2, p. 90. Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky: Passed at the Session Which Was Begun and Held in the City of Frankfort, on Saturday the 31st of December, 1853, and Ended Friday the 10th of March, 1854</em> (Frankfort, KY: A. G. Hodges, 1854), volume 1, chapter 9, p. 214. “Kentucky Contested Election,” in <em>The Miscellaneous Documents of the House of Representatives, Printed During the First Session of the Thirty-Sixth Congress</em> (Washington. D.C.: Thomas H. Ford, 1860), p. 583. Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Cumberland County, Burkesville, p.5. Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States (1880), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Cumberland County, Burkesville, District 32, p. 110.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
