<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000819">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George W. Dunlap</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000819">
                    <persName>
                      George W. Dunlap
                        (Representative)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1813-02-22"></birth>
                      <death when="1880-06-06"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney and politician. Graduate from Transylvania University in 1834. Studied law and admitted to the bar 1838. Practiced law in Lancaster, Kentucky. Married to Nancy E. Jennings Dunlap. Father of Eugenia S. Dunlap Potts, Mary Dunlap Denny, John Jennings Dunlap, George W. Dunlap, Jr., Woodford G. Dunlap, Victor Dunlap, and Theodore Dunlap. Served as a master commissioner of the Garrard County Circuit Court from 1843 to 1874. Elected as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1853 to 1855. Served as an elector for the Whig Party and for the American “Know Nothing” Party in 1856. Served as a member of the 1861 Board State Convention. Served the Sixth Congressional District of Kentucky as a Unionist member of the United States House of Representative from 1861 to 1863. Returned to Lancaster, Kentucky to practice law. Served as a presidential elector in 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Dunlap, George Washington,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=D000542) (accessed December 15, 2016); Charles Lanman, <em>Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States</em> (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 149; Zachariah Frederick Smith, <em>The History of Kentucky: From Its Earliest Discovery and Settlement, to the Present Date . . . Its Military Events and Achievements, and Biographic Mention of Its Historic Characters</em> (Courier-Journal Job Printing Company, 1892), 836; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Garrard County, The First Division; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Garrard County, Town of Lancaster, p. 12; Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States (1880), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Garrard County, Lancaster, p. 45; “George Washington Dunlap,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=6864455) (accessed December 15, 2016).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
