<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000828">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John White Stevenson</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000828">
                    <persName>
                      John White Stevenson
                        (Representative)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1812-05-04"></birth>
                      <death when="1886-08-10"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Virginia-born, Kentucky attorney and politician. Educated at Hampden-Sidney Academy and graduated from the University of Virginia in 1834. Studied law and was admitted to the bar. Practiced law in Vicksburg, Mississippi and Covington, Kentucky. Married to Sibella Winston Stevenson. Father of Mary Winston Stevenson Colston, Sally Coles Stevenson Colston, Andrew Stevenson, Judith Stevenson, and John White Stevenson, Jr. Served as Kenton County attorney. Served as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1845 to 1849. Served as a delegate to the 1849 Kentucky Constitutional Convention. Appointed as a commissioner to revise the Civil and Criminal Code of Kentucky in 1850-51. Served as a Democratic Party presidential elector in 1852 and 1856. Served the Tenth Congressional District of Kentucky as a Democratic member of the United States House of Representative from 1857 to 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Stevenson, John White,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=S000894) (accessed January 6, 2017); Charles Lanman, <em>Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States</em> (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 476; “Stevenson, John White,” <em>The Kentucky Encyclopedia</em>, ed. John E. Kleber (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 1992), 854; “Graduates of the University of Virginia” in Edmund Ruffin, ed., <em>The Farmers’ Register</em>, vol. 2 (Shellbanks, Va.: Edmund Ruffin, Proprietor, 1835), 252-253; “John White Stevenson, Sr.,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=6860303) (accessed January 6, 2017); “Ex-Gov. Stevenson,” <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), August 11, 1886; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, 4th District, The City of Covington; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, 7 Ward Covington City, p. 406.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
