<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00001579">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Pleasant Hines</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00001579">
                    <persName>
                      Pleasant Hines
                        (Warren County farmer and Police Judge of Bowling Green)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1798-05-19"></birth>
                      <death when="1880-02"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Warren County, Kentucky farmer and Police Judge of Bowling Green. Charlotte County, Virginia native. Married Hetta Jackson Hines in 1817. Married Tabitha A. Hines. Father of William H. Hines. Served in the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1857 to 1859. Held thirty-three slaves in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <em>History of Kentucky, Volume II</em> (Covington, KY: Collins and Company, 1878), p. 738. Jordan Dodd, <em>Kentucky Marriages, 1802-1850</em>, Ancestry, Warren County, 1817. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, District 1, p. 21. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, District 1. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, Bowling Green, District 2, p. 24. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, District 2, p. 7. Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, Bowling Green, p. 69. “William Pleasant Hines,” <em>Find A Grave</em>, April 24, 2010, Memorial no. 51536333. Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States (1880), Mortality Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, p. 695.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
