<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004500">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Peter B. Bruner, Jr.</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004500">
                    <persName>
                      Peter B. Bruner, Jr.
                        (Hancock County farmer)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1806-01-27"></birth>
                      <death when="1879-02-07"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky farmer. Lived in Hancock County, Kentucky in 1860. Married to Hannah Davis Bruner. Father of George W. Bruner, Cynthia E. Bruner, Davis T. Bruner, Robert T. Bruner, Henry V. Bruner, Charles M. Bruner, Martha E. Bruner, Patsey A. Bruner, Artimissa P. Bruner, and Lucretia C. Bruner. Member of the Masonic Order at Hancock Lodge, No. 115 in Hawesville, Kentucky.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Proceedings of the Grand Lodge of Kentucky, at a Grand Annual Communication, in the City of Louisville, Commencing on Monday, the 21st Day of October, 1867</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: Frankfort Commonwealth, 1867), 111-112; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County, p. 33; Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County, Pellville Town, p. 1; &quot;Peter B. Bruner,&quot; (https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=41027902&amp;ref=acom) (accessed on April 13, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
