<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000812">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George Helm Yeaman</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000812">
                    <persName>
                      George Helm Yeaman
                        (Representative)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1829-11-01"></birth>
                      <death when="1908-02-23"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney, politician, and lecturer of constitutional law. Educated in preparatory school. Studied law and admitted to the bar in 1851. Practiced law in Owensboro, Kentucky. Married to Lillia Pegram Triplett Yeaman in 1855. Father of Robert T. Yeaman, Stephen M. Yeaman, Lelia P. Yeaman, Jr., Virginia L. Yeaman Remnitz, and Anna H. Yeaman. Elected as Daviess County Court Judge in 1851. Elected as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives in 1861. Served the Second Congressional District of Kentucky as Unionist member of the United States House of Representative from December 1861 to March 1865. Served as United States Minister to Denmark from 1865 to 1870.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “George Helm Yeaman,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=Y000015) (accessed December 5, 2016); “George Helm Yeaman Dies in New York,” <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), February 23, 1908; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Daviess County, District No 1, p. 35-36; Tenth Manuscript Census of the United States (1880), Population Schedules, New York, New York County, New York City, p. 13.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
