<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006191">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert Byington Mitchell</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006191">
                    <persName>
                      Robert Byington Mitchell
                        (Brigader General Union )
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1823-07-04"></birth>
                      <death when="1882-01-26"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born in Mansfield, Ohio, April  4, 1823. Studied law in Mount Vernon. Started a practice in Mansfield, and served in the Mexican War as a Second Lieutenant in the 2nd Ohio Volunteers. Elected mayor of Mount Gilead, Ohio in 1855. Moved to Linn County in the Kansas Territory as a free state settler. Served in the territorial legislature, as a delegate to the Leavenworth convention, as treasurer of the territory, and as a delegate to the Democratic National Convention of 1860 in Charleston. Commissioned  Colonel of the 2nd Kansas Volunteer Infantry. Wounded at the battle of Wilson&#39;s Creek in August. Appointed him a Brigadier General to rank from April 8, 1862, and he was given command of a mixed Brigade at Fort Riley. At the battle of Perryville, Kentucky, in October he commanded the 9th Division of Gilbert&#39;s Corps. He was then stationed at Nashville for a number of months and during the Chickamauga Campaign acted as Chief of Cavalry of Thomas&#39; Army of the Cumberland. Just before the battle of Chattanooga, he was ordered to Washington, D.C. for court martial duty. Commanded the District of Nebraska, then the District of North Kansas, and finally the District of Kansas from 1864 to 1865. Died in Washington, D.C. on January 26, 1882.  </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>&quot;Robert Byington Mitchell&quot;, <em>Arlington Cemetery Website</em> http://www.arlingtoncemetery.net/rbmitchell.htm</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
