<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002379">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">General William Tecumseh Sherman</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002379">
                    <persName>
                      General William Tecumseh Sherman
                        (General)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1820-02-08"></birth>
                      <death when="1891-02-14"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born in Lancaster, Ohio. Older brother of U.S. Senator of Ohio, John Sherman. William Sherman graduated from West Point in 1840. Fought the Seminoles in Florida. Administrative Officer in California during the Mexican-American War. Resigned U.S. Army in 1853. Moved to California to work in banking, career ruined by Panic of 1857. Older brother, Sen. John Sherman gets William a commission as Colonel in U.S. Army after Civil War broke out. </p>

<p>Fought in First Battle of Bull Run (July 21, 1861). After the battle, Sherman earned a commission as a Brigadier General. Gained command in Kentucky in October 1861. Removed from this command and sent to work under General Ulysses S. Grant as a divisional commander. Sherman performed well at the Battle of Shiloh (April 6-7, 1862) and was promoted to Major General. Helped Grant lead campaign to capture Vicksburg (1862-1863). Sherman received command of the Army of Tennessee. Fought in the Chattanooga campaign. Sherman took Atlanta on September 2, 1864. Lead 62,000 troops on his famous &quot;March to the Sea&quot; from Atlanta to Savannah, Georgia. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Charlton W. Tebeau, &quot;William Tecumseh Sherman,&quot; <em>Encyclopedia Brittanica</em>, https://www.britannica.com/biography/William-Tecumseh-Sherman accessed 03/15/2017.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
