<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006215">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George B. McClellan</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006215">
                    <persName>
                      George B. McClellan
                        (Union General)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1826-12-03"></birth>
                      <death when="1885-10-29"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>McClellan was born on December 3, 1826 in Philadelphia. McClellan attended the University of Pennsylvania in 1840, accepted to The United States Military Academy at West Point in 1842 and graduated second in his class in 1846. Obtained his commission after graduating as brevet second lieutenant in the United States Army Corps of Engineers.  McClellan then served in the Mexican-American War where he was promoted to brevet first lieutenant. He was stationed at several locations after the Mexican-American War including West Point, Fort Delaware, Delaware, Fort Smith, Arkansas, and the Washington Territory as an engineer and surveyor. . He resigned his commission on January 16, 1857. He then moved into the railroad industry and became the chief engineer and vice president of the Illinois Central Railroad. in 1860, he became the president of the Ohio Mississippi Railroad. He supported Stephen A. Douglas in the 1860 presidential election. He married Marry Ellen Marcy Nelly on May 22, 1860 in New York City. </p>

<p>At the outbreak of the Civil War, McClellan was commissioned as the Ohio militia major general of volunteers on April 23, 1861. On May 3 of the same year he became the commander of the Department of the Ohio. on May 14, McClellan was promoted to major general of the regular army. on November 1, 1861 he was promoted to general-in-chief when Winfield Scott retired in addition to his duties as army commander. He commanded the army in the Peninsula Campaign and the Maryland Campaign, culminating in the battle of Antietam. Due to his inability to peruse Lee, President Lincoln removed him from his command on November 5, 1862. in 1864, McClellan was nominated as the Democratic candidate for President. He lost the election to Abraham Lincoln. McClellan died on October 29, 1885 in West Orange, New Jersey.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Ezra J. Warner, <em>Generals in Blue: Lives of the Union Commanders</em> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1964), 290-292; Stephen W. Sears, <em>George B. McClellan: The Young Napoleon,</em> (New York: Da Caop Press, 1999); <em>Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedules, New York , Orange County, Cornwall, p. 360.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
