<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003176">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Franklin Hawes, Sr.</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003176">
                    <persName>
                      William Franklin Hawes, Sr.
                        (Hancock County farmer and captain of the Hancock County Home Guard)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1819-04-28"></birth>
                      <death when="1889-12-07"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky farmer, soldier, and coal baron. Lived in Hancock County in 1860. Married to Aurelia C. Hawes. Owned twenty-three enslaved persons in 1860. Father of William F. Hawes, Jr., Aurelia Hawes, Ann Hawes, Amelia Hawes, Ed Hawes, and Sue Hawes. Incorporated the Hawes Coal and Manufacturing Company in Hancock County in 1854. Served as a captain in the Hancock County Home Guards in 1861. Served as a captain in the First Kentucky Cavalry (Co. D) (C.S.A.) under General Ben Hardin Helm in 1861 and 1862. Served as a major and assistant quartermaster under J. M. Hawes Command from June 1862 to May 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>William F. Hawes, Sr., 1st Kentucky Cavalry (C.S.A.), Compiled Service Record, (https://www.fold3.com/image/88551591) (accessed on march 30, 2017); William F. Hawes, Sr., General Staff and Officers, Compiled Service Record, (https://www.fold3.com/image/70891988) (accessed on march 30, 2017); &quot;An Act to Incorporate the Hawes Coal Company, in Hancock County&quot; <em>Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</em>, vol. 2 (Frankfort, Ky.: A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1854), 283-286; &quot;The Hawesville Coal Mines,&quot; <em>Daily Courier</em> (Louisville, Ky.), September 20, 1854; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County, p. 35 ; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hancock County, p. 2; &quot;Major William Franklin Hawes,&quot; (https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=75612019&amp;ref=acom) (accessed on March 30, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
