<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000821">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Brutus Junius Clay</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000821">
                    <persName>
                      Brutus Junius Clay
                        (Representative)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1808-07-01"></birth>
                      <death when="1878-10-11"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky farmer, stockman, and politician. Graduated from Centre College. Moved to Bourbon County, Kentucky to pursue agriculture. Married twice, first to Amelia McClanahan Field Clay and following her death in 1843, to her sister Ann Marie Field Clay. Father of Martha Clay, Brutus Junius Clay, Christopher Field Clay, Brutus Junius Clay, Green Clay, Ezekiel Field Clay, and Cassius Marcellus Clay, Jr. Owned 132 enslaved persons in 1860. Elected as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives in 1840 and 1860. Served as president of the Bourbon County Agricultural Association from 1840 to 1876. Served as president of the Kentucky Agricultural Association from 1853 to 1861. Served the Seventh Congressional District of Kentucky as a Unionist member of the United States House of Representative from 1863 to 1865, serving as chair of the Committee on Agriculture. Returned to Paris, Kentucky.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Clay, Brutus Junius,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=C000479) (accessed December 16, 2016); Charles Lanman, <em>Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States</em> (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 97; “Clay, Brutus Junius,” <em>The Kentucky Encyclopedia</em>, ed. John E. Kleber (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 1992), 199; Zachariah Frederick Smith, et al., <em>The Clay Family</em> 14 (J. P. Morton and Company, 1899), 120-121; “Brutus Junius Clay,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=15490047) (accessed December 16, 2016); Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon County, District No 1; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon County, Eastern Division, p. 21; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Bourbon County, Eastern Division, p. 10-12.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
