<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000850">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Benjamin Franklin Bradley</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000850">
                    <persName>
                      Benjamin Franklin Bradley
                        (Representative (Confederate))
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1835-10-05"></birth>
                      <death when="1897-01-22"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney, soldier, and politician. Educated at Georgetown College and graduated from the law department of Transylvania University in 1846. Admitted to the bar and practiced law in Georgetown, Kentucky and Chicago, Illinois. Recruited and served as a regimental adjutant and brigade adjutant with the Third Kentucky Volunteers in the Mexican War. Married to Emily Mary Sanders Bradley. Father of Anna Bradley, Mathew S. Bradley, Victor F. Bradley, Betty Sanders Bradley, and John Bradley. Moved to Chicago to practice law and work as a land agent from 1854 to 1861. Served as a major in the First Battalion of Kentucky Mounted Rifleman of the Confederate States of America from 1861 to 1864. Served the Eleventh Congressional District as a member of the Second Confederate Congress in the House of Representatives from 1864 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Ezra J. Warner and W. Buck Yearns, <em>Biographical Register of the Confederate Congress</em> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1975), 29-30; Lewis Collins and Richard Collins, <em>History of Kentucky</em>, vol. 1 (Collins &amp; Company, 1882), 353; “Maj. Benjamin Franklin Bradley,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=9398035) (accessed January 23, 2017); “Maj. Ben F. Bradley: Dies at Georgetown after Several Week’s Illness,” <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), January 23, 1897; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Illinois, Cook County, 5th Ward in the City of Chicago, p. 279-280; Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Town of Georgetown, p. 5.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
