<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003309">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert Cobb</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003309">
                    <persName>
                      Robert Cobb
                        (Lawyer, Eddyville KY)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1836-05-21"></birth>
                      <death when="1914-07-20"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born in Eddyville, Ky on May 21, 1836. Studied Law at the University of Virginia from 1855 to 1856. Began practicing law in Eddyville in 1858. Enlisted in CSA in June of 1861. Fought in Company F, 3rd Kentucky Infantry as First Lieutenant. Transferred to Artillery and became Captain of Cobb&#39;s Battery. on February 22, 1864 Cobb was commissioned as Major of Artillery and began command of Cobb&#39;s Battalion of Artillery until the end of the war. During his service he fought at Shiloh Murfreesboro, and Vicksburg, among other engagements. on August 3, 1865 he married Virginia Walker. Died in Wichita Falls, Wichita County, Texas on July 20, 1914.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>John W. Leonard, ed., <em>Who&#39;s Who in America: A Biographical Dictionary of Notable Living Men and Women of the United States</em> (Chicago: A. N. Marquis &amp; Co., 1902), 220; <em>Find A Grave</em>, &quot;Capt Robert H Cobb, Sr (May 1836 - July 20, 1914),&quot; Memorial #27252713, https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=27252713&amp;ref=acom (accessed June 27, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
