<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007395">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James  B. McPherson</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007395">
                    <persName>
                      James  B. McPherson
                        (Union General )
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1828-11-14"></birth>
                      <death when="1864-07-22"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>McPherson was born on November 14, 1828 in Sandusky County, Ohio. He graduated from West Point  in 1849 and was commissioned to the Corps of Engineers.He taught practical engineering at West Point for a year before being stationed in California. With the beginning of the Civil War, McPherson was first assigned to help work on fortifications in Boston and then became Aide-de-camp to Major General H. W. Halleck in Missouri. He was later being assigned to General Ulysses S. Grant as chief engineer in the Tennessee campaign. He participated in the battles of Fort Henry and Fort Donelson as well as the battles of Shiloh and Corinth prior to being promoted to major general of volunteers. After the fall of Vicksburg in 1863, McPherson was promoted to Brigadier General. in March 1864, he was put in charge of the Army of the Tennessee under General William T. Sherman in his campaign to Atlanta. While in this role, McPherson was shot and killed by a Confederate guerrilla on July 22, 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Jeff Wallenfeldt, ed., <em>The American Civil War and Reconstruction: People, Politics, and Power</em> (New York: Britannica Educational Publishing, 2010), 144; <em>Find A Grave</em>, &quot;James Birdseye McPherson (November 14, 1828 - July 22, 1864),&quot; Memorial #4423, acom (accessed June 22, 2017); Margaret E. Wagner, Gary W. Gallagher, and Paul Finkelman, eds., <em>The Library of Congress Civil War Desk Reference</em> (New York: Grad Central Press, 2002), 416 - 417.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
