<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004767">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Gideon Johnson Pillow</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004767">
                    <persName>
                      Gideon Johnson Pillow
                        (CSA Brig. Gen.)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1806-06-08"></birth>
                      <death when="1878-10-08"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born on June 8, 1806 in Williamson County, Tennessee. Graduated from the University of Nashville in 1827. Moved to Columbia Tennessee to practice law. Married Elixabeth martin on March 24, 1831. Appointed District Attorney General in 831. Pillow served in the Tennessee militia from 1833 to 1836 as a brigadier general. At the outbreak of the Mexican-American war, Pillow joined the United States Army and was appointed Brigadier General by his friend President Polk, on July 1, 1846. Promoted to major general of volunteers on April 13, 1847.Was wounded twice during the war. Pillow got into a conflict with the commander of the military forces, Winfield Scott, that eventually ended in his discharge from the army on July 20, 1848. he participated in local and national politics in the period between the Mexican American War and the Civil War, but never was elected to office himself. He was a land speculator and by 1860, was possibly the wealthiest man in Tennessee. He joined the Confederate Army on May 9, 1861 and was appointed Senior Major General of the Provisional Army of Tennessee. In July 1861, he was appointed Brigadier Genreal in the Confederate States Army, under the command of Major General Leonidas Polk and General Albert Sidney Johnston. Pillow, under the order of Polk, led Confederate forces into Kentucky on September 3, 1861. This event would break Kentucky&#39;s neutrality agreement and push Kentucky closer to the Union. Pillow would command at the Battle of Belmont and the Battle of Fort Donelson. He was suspended by Jefferson Davis for his actions at the battle of Fort Donelson, but maintained a command in the Confederate Army. He later served under Major General John C. Breckenridge in the Army of Tennessee at the Battle of Stone River. Pillow died on October 8, 1878 in Helena, Arkansas. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Nathaniel Cheairs Hughes Jr., <em>The Battle of Belmont: Grant Strikes South,</em> (Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press, 1991), 30; Ezra J. Warner, <em>Generals in Gray: Lives of the Confederate Commanders</em>, (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1959), 241; Ed. C. Bearss, &quot;Pillow Gideon Johnson,&quot; in <em>Historical Times Illustrated Encyclopedia of he Civil War, Patricia L. Faust, ed., (New York: Harper &amp; Row, 1986); Nathaniel Cheairs Hughes Jr. and Roy P. Stonesifer, *The Life and Wars of Gideon J. Pillow,</em> (Chapel Hill: University of North Carolina Press, 1993). <em>Find A Grave</em>, &quot;Gen Gideon Johnson Pillow (June 8, 1806 - October 8, 1878),&quot; Memorial #11052, https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GSln=Pillow&amp;GSfn=Gideon+&amp;GSmn=Johnson&amp;GSbyrel=all&amp;GSdyrel=all&amp;GSob=n&amp;GRid=11052&amp;df=all&amp; (accessed June 26, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
