<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002559">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Andrew Barnett</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002559">
                    <persName>
                      Andrew Barnett
                        (Marion County and Green County Attorney; Commonwealth&#39;s Attorney)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1827-03-04"></birth>
                      <death when="1910-02-11"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney. Lived in Greensburg, Kentucky and Marion County, Kentucky between 1858 and 1863. Educated at Georgetown College (Kentucky) and Harvard University. Graduated from the Louisville Law School in 1848. Married to Francis Katherine &quot;Kate&quot; Tyler Barnett. Member of the Democratic Party. Served as commonwealth&#39;s attorney for the 5th Kentucky Judicial District from 1858 to 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Marion County, District No. 2 Lebanon, p. 104; &quot;Andrew Barnett,&quot; (https://findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=58907114) (accessed on March 16, 2017); <em>Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: A. G. Hodges, Public Printer, 1858), xxiv; <em>The National Almanac and Annual Record for the Year 1863 (Philadephia: George W. Childs, 1863), 460; Charles Kerr, ed., _History of Kentucky</em> (Chicago: The American Historical Society, 1922), 191.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
