<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000814">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Clayton Anderson</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000814">
                    <persName>
                      William Clayton Anderson
                        ()
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1826-12-26"></birth>
                      <death when="1861-12-23"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney and politician. Educated in private schools and graduated from Centre College in 1845. Studied law and admitted to the bar. Practiced law in Lancaster, Kentucky and Danville, Kentucky. Married to Amelia Owsley Rodes Anderson Yerkes. Father of Lizzie Anderson, Clifton Anderson, and William C. Anderson, Jr. Owned ten enslaved persons in 1860. Elected as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1851 to 1853. Served as presidential elector for the American Party ticket in 1856. Served the Fourth Congressional District of Kentucky as an Opposition Party member of the United States House of Representative from 1859 to 1861. Elected as a Unionist member of the Kentucky House of Representatives in 1861 and died in Frankfort on the last day of the adjourned legislative session of November 1861 to December 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Anderson, William Clayton,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=A000237) (accessed December 7, 2016); <em>Daily Louisville Democrat</em> (Louisville, Ky.), December 24, 1861; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, p. 45; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, The Second District, p. 6.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
