<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000860">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Samuel Howard Ford</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000860">
                    <persName>
                      Samuel Howard Ford
                        (Provisional Congress of the Confederate States)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1819-02-19"></birth>
                      <death when="1905-07-05"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>An English-born Baptist minister. Graduated from Missouri State University in 1843 and ordained a Baptist minister. Belonged to the Calvinist tradition. Married to Sallie Rochester Ford. Father of Samuel Ford. Served as minister in the Missouri cities of Jefferson City, St. Louis, and Cape Girardeau from 1844 to 1847. Served as co-editor of the Western Recorder with Dr. John L. Waller. Served as co-editor and, following Waller’s death, editor of Christian Repository. Served as minister of the Gum Spring Baptist Church in McCracken County, Kentucky of the West Union Association in 1852. Served as minister of the East Baptist Church, Long Run Baptist Church, and Floyds Fork Baptist Church in Louisville, Kentucky of the Long Run Association from 1853 to 1861. Served as a minister in Memphis, Tennessee in 1861. Served as a member of the Provisional Congress of the Confederate States from 1861 to 1862. Served as a minister in Mobile, Alabama from 1863 to 1865. Returned to Memphis as a minister in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Ezra J. Warner and W. Buck Yearns, <em>Biographical Register of the Confederate Congress</em> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1975), 87-88; Lewis Collins and Richard Collins, <em>History of Kentucky</em>, vol. 1 (Collins &amp; Company, 1882), 353; John H. Spencer, <em>A History of Kentucky Baptists: from 1769 to 1885</em> (Cincinnati: J. R. Baumes, 1885), 191-192; John Lansing Burrows, <em>American Baptist Register</em>, for 1852 (Philadephia: American Baptist Publication Society, 1853), 127; “Samuel Howard Ford,” (https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=23361) (accessed January 26, 2017); Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, McCracken County, District No 1; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, 4th Ward City of Louisville, p. 79. </p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
