<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002746">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Overton Moore</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002746">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas Overton Moore
                        (Louisiana Governor 1859)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1804-04-10"></birth>
                      <death when="1876-06-25"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born April 10, 1804 in Sampson County, North Carolina. Moved to Rapides Parish, Louisiana in 1829. In Louisiana, he owned a Plantation. Moore was elected to Louisiana State House of Representatives in 1848. He was elected to Louisiana State Senate in 1856. Moore was a Democrat. He served on the education committee that helped to establish Louisiana State University and Agriculture and Mechanical College.  Elected governor of Louisiana in 1859. Supported Secession. In May 1862, Moore and the state government relocated to Opelousas to evade Union forces in the state. Moore’s governorship ended in 1864, after which he returned to his plantation. He soon had to leave his plantation as Union forces were moving through and burned it. Moore died on June 25, 1876 in Alexandria, Louisiana.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>John David Winters, <em>The Civil War in Louisiana</em> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1991), 4; “Governor Thomas Overton Moore,” National Governors Association, https://www.nga.org/cms/home/governors/past-governors-bios/page<em>louisiana/col2-content/main-content-list/title</em>moore<em>thomas.default.html; Spencer C. Tucker, ed., <em>American Civil War: The Definitive Encyclopedia and Documents Collection</em> (Santa Barbara, California: ABC-CLIO, 2013), 1321; _Find A Grave</em>, &quot;Thomas Overton Moore (April 10, 1804 - June 25, 1876),&quot; Memorial #8385593, https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=8385593&amp;ref=acom (accessed June 27, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
