<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000283">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George Douglas Blakey</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000283">
                    <persName>
                      George Douglas Blakey
                        ()
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1809-02-21"></birth>
                      <death when="1885-12-13"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kentucky farmer, writer, and politician. Married to Lucy L. Thomas Blakey. Father of Elizabeth Patterson Blakey, James Reuben Blakey, Sallie George Blakey McCarley, William Churchill Blakey, Pamelia Margaret Blakey Duncan, and Reuben Thomas Blakey. Owned thirty-three enslaved persons in 1850 and twenty-one in 1860. Member of the Republican Party and Union Party. Member of the Bowling Green Lodge of the Independent Order of Odd Fellows. Ran as the Emancipation Party vice presidential candidate with Cassius Marcellus Clay in 1848. Served as a senatorial delegate for the Republican Party of Kentucky in 1858. Served as a member of the Union Executive Committee of Kentucky in 1865. Lived in Bowling Green, Kentucky in 1865. Appointed by President Andrew Johnson as one of three Commissioners to make awards to loyal slaveowners whose slaves enlisted in the Union Army.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>KYR-0002-022-0001; “Death of George D. Blakey,” <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), December 15, 1885; “Union State Convention at Frankfort,” <em>The Commonwealth</em> (Frankfort, Ky.), January 6, 1865; “Black Republicanism in Kentucky,” <em>Daily Courier</em> (Louisville, Ky.), November 18, 1859; “Independent Order of Odd Fellows,” <em>Daily Courier</em> (Louisville, Ky.), July 22, 1854; “Loyal Owners of Kentucky Slaves,” <em>Daily Courier</em> (Louisville, Ky.), October 25, 1866; Katy Haden, “Descendants of Anthony Haden,” (http://freepages.genealogy.rootsweb.ancestry.com/~katy/haden/b821.html) (accessed January 31, 2017); Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Logan County, District No 2; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Logan County, Russellville District No 2, p. 113; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Logan County, Russellville District No 2, p. 24.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
