<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000831">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Guthrie</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>James N. McAllister</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>James N. McAllister</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000831">
                    <persName>
                      James Guthrie
                        (Senator)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1792-12-05"></birth>
                      <death when="1869-03-13"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney, businessman, and politician. Attended McAllister’s Academy and Bardstown Academy. Owned flatboats and commenced trade in New Orleans, Louisiana. Studied law and admitted to the bar in 1817. Moved to Louisville in 1820 when he was appointed The Commonwealth’s Attorney by Governor John Adair. While living in Louisville he became a wealthy slaveholder. Practiced law in Bardstown, Kentucky and Louisville, Kentucky. Married to Eliza Churchhill Prather Guthrie. Father of Mary Elizabeth Guthrie Caperton, Ann Augusta Guthrie Caldwell, and Sarah Julia Guthrie Smith. Served as Commonwealth’s attorney for Jefferson County in 1820. Served as a member of the City of Louisville Board of Trustees. Served as a Jacksonian Democratic member of the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1827 to 1831. Served as a member of the Kentucky Senate from 1831 to 1840. Served as a member of the 1849 Kentucky Constitutional Convention from Jefferson County, Kentucky. Founded and served as president of the University of Louisville. Served as Secretary of the Treasury under President Franklin Pierce from 1853 to 1857. Employed by the Louisville &amp; Nashville Railroad Company—serving as president from 1860 to 1868. Served as president of the Louisville and Portland Canal Company. Served as a delegate to the 1861 peace convention in Washington, District of Columbia. Served the Commonwealth of Kentucky as a Democratic member of the United States Senate from 1865 to 1868.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Baber, George. “James Guthrie: Lawyer, Financier and Statesman: The Outline of a Great Kentuckian.” <em>The Register of the Kentucky State Historical Society</em>, Vol. 10. Frankfort, Kentucky: The Register of the Kentucky State Historical Society, 1912. 9-12; Cotterill, Robert S. “James Guthrie - Kentuckian, 1792-1869.” <em>Register of Kentucky State Historical Society</em> 20, no. 60 (September, 1922). 290-296; Robertson, Gabrielle. James Guthrie. Chicago: Univeristy of Chicago Dissertation, 1920; Wells, Donald R. “James Guthrie.” Biographical Dictionary of the United States Secretaries of the Treasury, 1789 - 1995. Ed. Bernard S. Katz and C. Daniel Vencill. Wesport, Connecticut: Greenwood Press, 1996. 182-185; <em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Guthrie, James,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=G000534) (accessed January 11, 2017); Charles Lanman, <em>Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States</em> (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 206; “James Guthrie,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=6654125  (accessed January 11, 2017); “Our Honored Dead: Funeral Obsequies of the Late James Guthrie,” <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), March 16, 1869; “Guthrie, James,” <em>The Kentucky Encyclopedia</em>, ed. John E. Kleber (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 1992), 396; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, 4th Ward City of Louisville, p. 70.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
