<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000837">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Stone Chrisman</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000837">
                    <persName>
                      James Stone Chrisman
                        (Representative (Confederate))
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1818-09-14"></birth>
                      <death when="1881-07-29"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney, farmer, and politician. Engaged in agriculture, studied law, and admitted to the bar in 1849.Practiced law in Monticello, Kentucky. Married to Lucy Nelson Bell Chrisman. Father of Alice Chrisman, Amelia B. Chrisman, Micah T. Chrisman, Fannie Chrisman, Lucy D. Chrisman, Jimonie Chrisman, Cabell P. Chrisman, and Frances Esler Chrisman Brown. Served as a member of the 1849 Kentucky Constitutional Convention from Wayne County, Kentucky. Served the Fourth Congressional District of Kentucky as a Democratic member of the United States House of Representative from 1853 to 1855. Served as a member of the Council of Ten in the Provisional Government of Kentucky. Served the Fifth Congressional District as a member of the First and Second Confederate Congress in the House of Representatives from 1862 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Ezra J. Warner and W. Buck Yearns, <em>Biographical Register of the Confederate Congress</em> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1975), 48; <em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Chrisman, James Stone,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=C000376) (accessed January 13, 2017); Charles Lanman, <em>Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States</em> (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 93; Lewis Collins and Richard Collins, <em>History of Kentucky</em>, vol. 1 (Collins &amp; Company, 1882), 353; “James Stone Chrisman,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=23543299) (accessed January 13, 2017); Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Wayne County, District No 1, p. 52-53; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Wayne County, Monticello, p. 6.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
