<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004704">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert &quot;Rob&quot; Morris</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004704">
                    <persName>
                      Robert &quot;Rob&quot; Morris
                        (A Massachusetts-born, Kentucky educator, editor, and Mason.)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1818-08-31"></birth>
                      <death when="1888-07-31"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Massachusetts-born, Kentucky educator, lecturer, editor, and Mason. Born as Robert Williams Peckham and changed name following the death of his parents. Lived in Oldham County, Kentucky in 1860. Married to Charlotte M. Mendenhall Morris. Father of John A. Morris, Charlotte F. Morris, Alfred W. Morris, Robert Morris, Sarah M. Morris, Ruth E. Morris, and Ella W. Morris. Worked as an educator in New York City for ten years in the 1830s and 1840s. Moved to Oxford Mississippi in the 1840s. Became a member of the Masonic Order in 1846 and a Knights Templar in 1850. Dedicated his life to Masonic institutions. Founder of the Order of the Eastern Star in 1850. Worked as a writer, editor, and poet on a variety of subjects. Author of <em>We Meet upon the Level</em> and many other works. Served as Grand Master of Masons of the Grand Lodge of Kentucky from 1858 to 1859. Appointed a U.S. Provost Marshal for Oldham County in 1862. Served in the Oldham County Home Guard in 1862. Raised a regiment of 90-day militia comprised of men from Oldham, Henry, Trimble, Owen, and adjacent counties in September 1862. Engaged in a speaking tour in New York in 1864. Returned to Oldham County, Kentucky.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Robert Morris, <em>The Poetry of Freemasonry</em> (Chciago: The Werner Company, 1895), xiii-xxiv; W. H. Perrin, J. H. Battle, and G. C. Kniffin, <em>Kentucky: A History of the State</em> (Louisville: F. A. Battey and Company, 1887), 830-831; Albert G. Mackey, William J. Hughan, and Edward L. Hawkins, <em>An Encyclopedia of Freemasonry and its Kindred Sciences</em>, vol. 2 (New York: The Masonic History Company, 1919), 493; &quot;Masonry&#39;s Great Loss: Death of Dr. Rob Morris, At Lagrange, Yesterday Morning,&quot; <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), August 1, 1888; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Oldham County, p. 51;; &quot;Dr. Rob Morris,&quot; (https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=20881522) (accessed on April 17, 2017); KYR-0001-028-0040.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
