<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003274">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Daniel H Hughes</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003274">
                    <persName>
                      Daniel H Hughes
                        (attorney, union county)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1833-07-17"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Daniel H. Hughes was born in Springfield, Kentucky, on July 17, 1833 to John Reed and Martha (Nantz) Hughes. He earned his Bachelor of Arts at Central College in Danville in 1852 and then went to work as an attorney with his uncle, Willis G. Hughes. Admitted to the bar in January 1855. Married Wright Parker in December 1855 and had seven children.  He lived at 213 West O&#39;Bannon Street Morganfield, KY. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>History of Union County, Kentucky. A Complete Account of the Settlement, Organization and Government of the County, Together with Facts and Figures Concerning the Society, Professions, Commerce, Industries, Agriculture, Coal, Railroads, Education, Religion, and Other Institutions and Recources of the County and Biographical Sketches of its Leading Citizens. Evansville, In: Courier Co., Printers, Binders and Engravers, 1886. 192-195.</p>

<p>United States Department of the Interior. National Registry of Historic Places Inventory—Nomination Form. Daniel H. Hughes House. <br>
https://npgallery.nps.gov/GetAsset?assetID=88003279-ced8-48fd-8735-397332b6958b</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
