<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004994">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Benjamin F. Blankenship</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004994">
                    <persName>
                      Benjamin F. Blankenship
                        (Harlan County soldier and farmer)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="c1833"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Virginia-born, Kentucky farmer and soldier. Lived in Harlan County, Kentucky in 1860. Married to Elizabeth Blankenship. Father of Emily Blankenship and Arthur Blankenship. Served as major of the Harlan County Battalion of Kentucky State Militia from October 1862 to January 1863. Served as a captain in the 47th Kentucky Mounted Infantry (Co. H) from October 1863 to December 1864. Served as postmaster of Poor Fork in Harlan County, Kentucky from June 1859 to July 1863, September 1865 to December 1868, and March 1869 to May 1870.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</em>, vol. 2 (Frankfort: John H. Harney, Public Printer, 1866), 470 and 883; <em>Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971</em>, NARA Microfilm Publication, M841, Records of the Post Office Department, Record Group Number 28, accessed on ancestry.com (Washington, D.C.: National Archives) (accessed on May 4, 2017); Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harlan County, p. 118.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
