<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006710">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Richard Fletcher Vinson</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006710">
                    <persName>
                      Richard Fletcher Vinson
                        (Lawrence Circuit and County Court Clerk)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1838"></birth>
                      <death when="1910"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisa farmer, and Lawrence County Circuit Court clerk and County clerk. Native of Kentucky. Married Georgia Ann Randall Vinson in 1859. Father of Victoria Vinson and Jennie Vinson. Lawrence County Circuit Court clerk and County Court clerk from 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>KYR-0001-004-1316. <em>Kentucky Birth, Marriage, and Death Records, 1852-1910</em>, Ancestry, Marriage, Greenup County, 1859. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Lawrence County, Louisa, p. 146. William T. Samuels, <em>Annual Report of the Auditor of Public Accounts, of the State of Kentucky, for the Fiscal Year Ending October 10, 1865</em> (Frankfort, KY: George D. Prentice, 1866), p. 12. D. Howard Smith, <em>Annual Report of the Auditor of Public Accounts, of the State of Kentucky, for the Fiscal Year Ending October 10, 1869</em> (Frankfort, KY: S. I. M. Major, 1869), p. 172. D. Howard Smith, <em>Annual Report of the Auditor of Public Accounts, of the State of Kentucky, for the Fiscal Year Ending October 10, 1870</em> (Frankfort, KY: S. I. M. Major, 1871), p. 162. Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Lawrence County, Louisa, p. 2. Stephanie Adkins, Mary Ellen Adkins Reid, and Linda Yates Holt, comp., <em>Pine Hill Cemetery, Louisa, Kentucky</em> (Paintsville, KY: Broadway Printers, 2007), 123. “Richard Fletcher Vinson,” <em>Find A Grave</em>, July 22, 2014, Memorial no. 133184825</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
