<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000829">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John William Menzies</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000829">
                    <persName>
                      John William Menzies
                        (Representative)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1819-04-12"></birth>
                      <death when="1897-10-03"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney and politician. Graduated from the University of Virginia in 1840.  Admitted to the bar in 1841 and practiced law in Covington, Kentucky. Married twice, first to Elizabeth Jane Butler Menzies and a second time to Samuella L. Peniston Menzies. Father of Fannie Butler Menzies Hawkins, Lily Menzies Barbour, Sallie Menzies Applegate, Finnell Whitley Menzies, Anne Menzies Spears, Katherine Menzies Kinsey, Elizabeth Menzies Simrall, Nelly Menzies VanWinkle, and John William Menzies, Jr. Served as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives in 1848 and 1855. Served the Tenth Congressional District of Kentucky as a Unionist member of the United States House of Representative from 1861 to 1863. Served as a delegate to the 1864 Democratic National Convention held in Chicago, Illinois.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Menzies, John William,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=M000641) (accessed January 10, 2017); Charles Lanman, <em>Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States</em> (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 340; “John William Menzies,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=7092790) (accessed January 10, 2017); “Judge J. W. Menzies Dead,” <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), October 4, 1897; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Kenton County, 3d Ward Covington City, p. 133; Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Pendleton County, Precinct No 1, p. 94.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
