<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007664">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Mortimer Murray Benton</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>James N. McAllister</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007664">
                    <persName>
                      Mortimer Murray Benton
                        (lawyer, mayor)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1807-12-31"></birth>
                      <death when="1885-03-04"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born in Benton, New York. Moved to Franklin County, Indiana around 1814. Studies law in Indiana, and later Cincinnati, Ohio. Moved to Covington, Kentucky and studied under Jefferson Phelps. In 1831 passed the bar and became an attorney. Married Angelina Clemons in 1832. Was the first mayor of Covington from 1834-1835, and later the city clerk. Resumed private practice until 1849, when he was elected to the Covington city council, President of the Covington &amp; Lexington Railroad from 1853-1856. During the lead up to the war Benton was pro-Union, and when the Civil War began Benton aligned with the Republican party. Representative in the Kentucky Legislature as a Union party member from 1863-1865. Ran for the Kentucky. Senate in 1865, and won the election. His political career ended when he was ejected from his position in 1866 after he lost a challenge regarding the legality of the election. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Jamie Crouch, &quot;M. M. Benton: Covington&#39;s First Mayor,&quot; <em>Bulletin of the Kenton County Historical Society</em> (May/June 2014). http://kentoncountyhistoricalsociety.org/data/documents/May-June-2014.pdf. Find a Grave, &quot;Mortimer Murray Benton (1807 - 1885) https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GSln=benton&amp;GSfn=m&amp;GSmn=m&amp;GSby=1840&amp;GSbyrel=before&amp;GSdyrel=all&amp;GSob=n&amp;GRid=92194202&amp;df=all&amp;. 1850; Census Place: Covington Ward 1, Kenton, Kentucky; Roll: M432_208; Page: 229B; Image: 465.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
