<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000924">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Mason Brown</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000924">
                    <persName>
                      John Mason Brown
                        ()
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1837-04-26"></birth>
                      <death when="1890-01-29"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kentucky attorney and soldier. Attended school with Mr. Sayre in Frankfort, Kentucky. Graduated from Yale College in 1856. Studied law with Thomas N. Lindsey. Admitted to the bar in 1858. Practiced law in St. Louis, Missouri and Frankfort, Kentucky. Married to Mary O. Preston Brown. Father of at least four children. Served as a major of the 10th Kentucky Cavalry from October 1862 to April 1863. Served as assistant inspector general with the rank of colonel of Kentucky from November 1863 to February 1864. Served as colonel of the 45th Kentucky Mounted Infantry from February 1864 to December 1864. Resumed practice of law in 1865 at Frankfort, Kentucky.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Obituary Records of Graduates of Yale University, (http://mssa.library.yale.edu/obituary<em>record/1859</em>1924/1889-90.pdf, 584-585) (accessed on February 16, 2017); H. Levin, (The Lawyers and Lawmakers of Kentucky) (Chicago: The Lewis Publishing Company, 1897), 209; “Died in His Prime: Col. John Mason Brown’s Illness Terminated By Death Yesterday,” <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), January 30, 1890; “Col John Mason Brown,” (https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=73732532) (accessed on February 16, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
