<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003045">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Barnet Fry</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003045">
                    <persName>
                      James Barnet Fry
                        (Union Provost Marshal General)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1827-02-22"></birth>
                      <death when="1894-07-11"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>An Illinois soldier. Married to Caroline Fry. Born in Carrollton, Illinois. Graduated from the United States Military Academy at West Point in 1847. Served garrison duty during the Mexican-American War. Served as adjutant of the United States Military Academy at West Point from 1854 to 1859. Served as chief of staff for General Irvin McDowell and General Don Carlos Buell. Ultimately served as provost marshal general of the United States from November 1862 to August 1866. At the close of the war, Fry had attained the rank of brevet major general, U.S. Army.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Ezra J. Warner, <em>Generals in Blue: Lives of the Union Commanders</em> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1988), 162-163; &quot;James Barnet Fry,&quot; (https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=6824&amp;ref=acom) (accessed March 28, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
