<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008148">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert Aitcheson Alexander</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008148">
                    <persName>
                      Robert Aitcheson Alexander
                        (Very wealthy Woodford Co, KY livestock breeder)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="c1819"></birth>
                      <death when="1867"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Residence: Woodford County, Kentucky. English-born son of Robert Alexander and Eliza Richardson. Owned &quot;Woodburn&quot; stock farm in Woodford County, Kentucky. Woodburn was the largest breeding establishment in the world, according to an 1867 newspaper report, where cattle, horses, and sheep were bred on this five thousand-acre estate. Alexander&#39;s herds included pure bred shorthorn cattle and Southdown sheep, both of which he began to import from England in 1850 and which gave his livestock holdings a national reputation. Also owned race horses. One of the wealthiest men in the United States at the time of his death in 1867. In addition to Woodburn, owned a large property in central Illinois, several blocks in Chicago, and a seventeen thousand-acre &quot;mineral tract&quot; in Muhlenberg County, Kentucky, located in the Adrie Iron Works of America. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</em> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Woodford County, KY, Jul 1863, p. 1, (Accessed via ancestry.com).</p>

<p>&quot;Robert Aitcheson Alexander,&quot; Louisville <em>Daily Journal</em>, 22 Nov 1867, 4. ProQuest Historical Newspapers.</p>

<p>William Preston Mangum, <em>A Kingdom for the Horse: The Legacy of R.A. Alexander and Woodburn Farms</em> (Harmony House Publishers, 1999) (preview accessed on google books)</p>

<p>William E. Railey, <em>History of Woodford County, Kentucky</em> (Frankfort, KY: Clearfield, 1938), 27-28 (accessed https://books.google.com/books?id=43jEKg6VTLYC&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=history+woodford+county+ky&amp;hl=en&amp;sa=X&amp;ved=0ahUKEwjlmbiS4r7VAhWI8CYKHX_zC2wQ6AEIKDAA#v=onepage&amp;q=alexander&amp;f=false)</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
