<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002598">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">M. D. West</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002598">
                    <persName>
                      M. D. West
                        (Quartermaster-general of Kentucky in 1861)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1816-03-20"></birth>
                      <death when="1866-02-24"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kentucky soldier. Served as quartermaster-general of Kentucky from August 1859 to October 1861. Commissioned as a prison inspector by Governor Magoffin on October 30, 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>&quot;Major M. D. West,&quot; <em>The Louisville Daily Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), March 1, 1866; “Annual Report of the Auditor of Public Accounts of the State of Kentucky, for the Fiscal Year Ending October 10, 1859,” (Frankfort, Ky.: Jno. B. Major, State Printer, 1860), 288; &quot;Beriah Magoffin, Executive Journal, Commission, M. D. West,&quot; November 19, 1861, Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor&#39;s official correspondence file, executive journal, 1859-1862,  MG<em>EJ-261,  Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives,  Frankfort,  KY.  Accessed via the Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition, KYR-0001-025-0266; :Lewis Collins and Richar H. Collins, _Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</em> (Covington, Ky.: Collins &amp; Co., 1882), 91 and 96; &quot;M D West,&quot; (https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GSln=West&amp;GSiman=1&amp;GScid=169757&amp;GRid=60293665&amp;) (accessed on March 17, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
