<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002782">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Lafayette Montgomery Flournay</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002782">
                    <persName>
                      Lafayette Montgomery Flournay
                        (Paducah, Kentucky)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1820-09-19"></birth>
                      <death when="1900-06-14"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Also Spelled Flournoy. Born in Powhatan County, Virginia. Graduated from Cumberland College, Princeton, Kentucky in 1840. Became a licensed lawyer in 1841. 1841 moved to Paducah, Kentucky. Editor of the West Kentuckian in Paducah from 1844 to 1849. Became President of Commercial Bank of Kentucky at Paducah, Kentucky in 1853. Was President of the Paducah Gaslight Company. Established the Paducah and Nashville Telegraph Company to form a telegraph line from Paducah, Kentucky to Nashville, Tennessee with J. W. Jones in 1856. Became president of the New Orleans and Ohio River Railroad Company in 1865.  Died in Spokane County, Washington. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Acts of The General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Vol. II (Frankfort; A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1856), 96; <em>The Biographical Encyclopedia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</em> (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 470; William McBean, New Orleans And Ohio Railroad, Illinois Central Railroad Company, and Mobile And Ohio Railroad Company, <em>A map of a part of the southern &amp; western states showing the contemplated route of the New Orleans &amp; Ohio Railroad and the Central Railroad of Illinois, also the route of the Mobile &amp; Ohio Railroad representing the most central, direct and practicable route for a great national and commercial highway between the Gulf of Mexico and the Great Northern Lakes, and by various branches and intersections with other Railways connecting with all the principal cities of the United States.</em> New Orleans, (1850). Map. Retrieved from the Library of Congress, https://www.loc.gov/item/98688725/; John E. L. Robertson and Ann E. Robertson, <em>Paducah Kentucky: A History</em> (Charleston: The History Press, 2014).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
