<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000321">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John Oliver McReynolds</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000321">
                    <persName>
                      John Oliver McReynolds
                        (Elkton, Todd County, Physician)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1827-03-30"></birth>
                      <death when="1905"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born on March 30, 1827 in Campbell County, Virginia. Graduated from Jefferson Medical College in Philadelphia in 1849.  Moved to Elkton where he worked as a Physician. Married Julia P Gorin in 1853. She died in that same year and in 1859, McReynolds married his second wife, Ellen M. Reeves. Died in 1905 in Elkton, Todd County, Kentucky.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Irving A Watson A. M., M. D., ed., <em>Physicians and Surgeons of America: A Collection of Biographical Sketches of the Regular Medical Profession</em> (Concord, New Hampshire: Republican Press Association, 1896), 39 - 40; <em>Find A Grave</em>, &quot;Dr. john Oliver McReynolds (March 1827 - 1905),&quot; Memorial #48332796,https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=48332796&amp;ref=acom (accessedJune 27, 2017).; <em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Todd County, District No. 2, p. 4; <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Todd County, Elkton, p. 71.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
