<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008195">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joseph Eggleston Johnston</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008195">
                    <persName>
                      Joseph Eggleston Johnston
                        (Confederate General)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1807-02-03"></birth>
                      <death when="1891-03-21"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A veteran of the Mexican War (1846-1848), quartermaster general of the United States Army, and a Confederate general during the Civil War. The highest-ranking U.S. Army officer to resign his commission at the start of the Civil War, on April 17, 1861. Upon resigning from the U.S. Army, Johnston accepted a commission as a Confederate brigadier general in charge of the garrison at Harpers Ferry. He later helped lead the Confederate victory at the First Battle of Manassas in July 1861. Appointed to full general by Jefferson Davis on August 31, 1861. Charged with the defense of the Confederate capital at Richmond. Led the attack against Union trips at the Battle of Seven Pines, May 31, 1862, a Confederate defeat. Appointed to the new Department of the West in November 1862. Davis later ordered Johnston to take command in Mississippi, to protect Vicksburg from the Union army. Johnston withdrew and Vicksburg fell on July 4, 1863. After this defeat, Jefferson Davis reduced Johnston&#39;s command to Mississippi and Alabama. Later, in February 1865, David reappointed Johnston to command the Army of Tennessee in North Carolina. Johnston surrendered his army to General William T. Sherman on April 26, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Bell, John L., Jr. and Brendan Wolfe, &quot;Joseph E. Johnston,&quot; in <em>Encyclopedia Virginia</em>, https://www.encyclopediavirginia.org/Johnston<em>Joseph</em>E<em>1807-1891#start</em>entry (accessed 11 Aug 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
