<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00001205">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William T, Taliaferro</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00001205">
                    <persName>
                      William T, Taliaferro
                        (War of 1812)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1795"></birth>
                      <death when="1871-03-22"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born in Newington, Orange County, Virginia in 1795. Enlisted in the Army at Camp Seneca, Forest Hills, Queens, New York. Fought at the Battle of Lake Erie, September 10, 1813, near Put-In-Bay, Ohio under Commodore Perry. Fought at the battle of Moravian Town, Canada West on October 5, 1813. studied medicine at University of Pennsylvania in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, in 1818. Became an ophthalmologist, performing cataract surgery in Maysville, Mason County, Kentucky. Moved to Cincinnati in 1841 and helped establish the second regular hospital in Cincinnati. He became the Chair of the Cincinnati College of Medicine. William Taliaferro died on March 22, 1871 in Cincinnati, Ohio.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Howard A. Kelly, <em>A Cyclopedia of American Medical Biography, Comprising the Lives of Eminent Deceased Physicians and Surgeons from 1610 to 1910</em> vol. 1 (Philadelphia: W. B. Saunders company, 1912), 1122; John M. Trowbridge, “’To Meet the Men at Any Element:’ The Kentucky Militia in the Battle of Lake Erie,” <em>Kentucky Ancestors: Genealogical Quarterly of the Kentucky Historical Society</em> 42, no. 1 (2006): 4; Edwin Porter Thompson, <em>A Young People’s History of Kentucky for Schools and General Reading</em> (St. Louis: A. R. Fleming Publishing Company, 1897), 197.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
