<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00008207">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Joseph Hardee</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00008207">
                    <persName>
                      William Joseph Hardee
                        (Confederate General)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1815-10-12"></birth>
                      <death when="1873-11-06"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born in Camden County, Georgia. Son of John Hardee and Sarah Ellis Hardee. Accepted to the United States Military Academy in 1834 and graduated in 1838. Fought in the Second Seminole War after graduation. Married Elizabeth Dummett on November 16, 1840. Served during the Mexican War, part of Zachary Taylor&#39;s &quot;Army of Occupation.&quot; He served in a number of actions and was brevetted twice for gallantry during Winfield Scott&#39;s campaign to capture Mexico City. After the Mexican War, then Secretary of War Jefferson Davis chose Hardee to write a new infantry tactics manual for the American army. Hardee&#39;s manual, <em>Rifle and Light Infantry Tactics</em> was completed in 1855 and remained the standard textbook for both Union and Confederate officers during the Civil War. Davis appointed Hardee commandant of cadets at the U.S. Military Academy, holding this position until 1860. After Georgia seceded from the Union, Hardee resigned his commission and joined the Confederate army. Appointed brigadier general on June 17, 1861 and received a command in northeastern Arkansas. Based at Pitman&#39;s Ferry, he organized a number of Arkansas regiments. Promoted to major general and given command of a division on October 21, 1861. Hardee and his division joined General Albert Sidney Johnston&#39;s Army of the Mississippi in March 1862. Commanded a corps at the Battle of Shiloh on April 6, 1862, where he was slightly wounded. Hardee was then transferred to Braxton Bragg&#39;s Army of the Tennessee. He fought at most of the Army&#39;s major battles and was promoted to lieutenant general on October 10, 1862. He served in the Atlanta campaign under the Army&#39;s new commander, Joseph E. Johnston. In September 1864, he assumed command of the Department of South Carolina, Georgia, and Florida, where he helped oppose Sherman&#39;s March to the Sea. Finally surrendered at Archdale, North Carolina, on April 26, 1865. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Mulloy, Clement, &quot;William Joseph Hardee (1815-1873)&quot;, <em>The Encyclopedia of Arkansas History &amp; Culture</em>, http://www.encyclopediaofarkansas.net/encyclopedia/entry-detail.aspx?entryID=5771 (accessed 12 August 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
