<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000810">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Samuel Oldham Peyton</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000810">
                    <persName>
                      Samuel Oldham Peyton
                        ()
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1804-01-08"></birth>
                      <death when="1870-01-04"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky physician, farmer, and politician. Educated in preparatory schools and graduated with a medical degree from Transylvania University in 1827. Married to Mary Worthington Kincheloe Peyton. Father of Mary Peyton Hoke, Samuel Peyton, Susan Peyton, Sarah Peyton, Craven Peyton, V. Wesley Peyton, Margaret Peyton, Lawrence “Frank” Peyton, and Valentine West Peyton. Member of the Democratic Party. Elected as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives in 1835. Served the Second Congressional District of Kentucky as member of the United States House of Representative from the 1847 to 1849 and 1857 to 1861.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Peyton, Samuel Oldham,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=P000284) (accessed December 2, 2016); Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Ohio County, Town of Hartford, p. 202; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Ohio County, District No 1; Harrison D. Taylor, <em>Ohio County, Kentucky, in the Olden Days: A series of old newspaper sketches of fragmentary history</em> (Baltimore: Clearfied Company, 2009), 78-79.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
