<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002354">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Fayette W. Alexander</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002354">
                    <persName>
                      Fayette W. Alexander
                        (Bank of Louisville)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1811-09-30"></birth>
                      <death when="1864-01-07"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born on September 30, 1811 in Henry County, Virginia. Fayette W. Alexander, merchant. Clerk in a store of general merchandise in Burkesville. Took charge of the Bank of Louisville until 1864. Married on January 8, 1840 to Nancy Gertrude King. Their ten children included Sally Wiles King (wife of Josiah Harris, a merchant of Adair County), Nancy Gertrude King (wife of Fayette W. Alexander), Sophia (wife of Almarine Alexander), John Q. A. King (elected lieutenant governor of Kentucky in 1863, and afterward a prominent member of the Paducah bar, who died in Denver, Col.), Ellen Hopkins (wife of Judge William F. Owsley), Mary Ann (wife of Clinton C. Alexander), Josephine Bonaparte ( the second wife of Almarine Alexander), Susan Victoria (wife of Louis Sweet, a wholesale clothing merchant of New York City), Milton  Wiles King (an attorney at law living in Missouri), and Burgess King  (who died at about the age of twenty-one, in 1857, while attending medical lectures at Lexington, Ky.). Died on January 7, 1864 in Louisville, Ky. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>J. H. Battle, W. H. Perrin, &amp; G. C. Kniffin, <em>Kentucky: A History of the State 4th ed.</em> (Louisville:Battey Publishing, 1887).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
