<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006222">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">George W. Berry</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006222">
                    <persName>
                      George W. Berry
                        (Captain &amp; provost marshal of the 6th Military District of Kentucky)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="unknown"></birth>
                      <death when="1864-06-17"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Harrison County, Kentucky farmer and soldier. Kentucky native. Married to Adelaide Jamison Berry on January 4, 1849. Father of Thomas Berry, Anastatia Berry, and Edward A. Berry. Commissioner of the Licking and Lexington Railroad in 1846. Postmaster of Berry&#39;s Station, Kentucky from 1856 to 1858Owned seven enslaved persons in 1860. Commissioner of the Colemansville and Williamson Turnpike Road in 1860. Captain and provost marshal of the 6th Military District of Kentucky in 1863. Captain and colonel of the Harrison County Home Guards in 1864. Killed at the Battle of Cynthiana on June 17, 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, p. 50; <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Harrison County, p. 10; William A. Penn, <em>Kentucky Rebel Town: The Civil War Battles of Cynthiana and Harrison County</em> (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2016); Jeanne Greiser, &quot;Battle of Falmouth&quot; in <em>The Encyclopedia of Northern Kentucky</em>, Paul A. Tenkotte and James C. Claypool, eds. (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 2009), 318; <em>Journal of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1846), 365-369; &quot;An Act to Incorporate the Colemansville and Williamstown Turnpike Road,&quot; <em>Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</em>, vol. 2 (Frankfort, Ky.: J. B. Major, State Printer, 1860), 320-322; <em>Record of Appointment of Postmasters, 1832-1971</em>, NARA Microfilm Publication, M841, Records of the Post Office Department, Record Group Number 28, accessed on ancestry.com (Washington, D.C.: National Archives) (accessed on May 17, 2017); Ancestry.com. Kentucky, County Marriages, 1783-1965 [database on-line]. Lehi, UT, USA: Ancestry.com Operations, Inc., 2016.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
