<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002032">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joshua Fry Bullitt</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002032">
                    <persName>
                      Joshua Fry Bullitt
                        (Louisville attorney and 3rd District Court of Appeals Judge)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1821-02-22"></birth>
                      <death when="1898-02-16"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Jefferson County attorney and Judge of the Third District Court of Appeals.  Attended Centre College and studied law at the University of Virginia. Admitted to the bar in 1844. Served as state representative from Louisville in 1851 and 1853. Partner in law with S. B. Smith in 1859. Elected Judge of the Third District Court of Appeals in 1861. Served as Chief Justice in 1864 and 1865. Arrested in July 1864 for his sympathy to the Confederacy, returned to Louisville on December 6, 1864. Fled to Canada and removed from office in June 1865. Married to Elizabeth B. Smith in 1846. Children included Johsua Fry Bullitt Jr.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>John J. McAfee, <em>Kentucky Politicians: sketches of representative Corncrackers and other miscellany</em> (Louisville, Kentucky: Press of the Courier-Journal job printing company, 1866), p. 36–40. John Livingston, <em>Livingston’s United States Law Register and Official Directory</em> (New York: John A. Gray, 1859), p. 300. H. Levin, ed., <em>The Lawyers and Lawmakers of Kentucky</em> (Chicago, IL: Lewis Publishing Company, 1897),87-89. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 2, p. 195. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, District 2, p. 4. Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, St. Matthews, Gillmans Precinct, p. 35. “Judge Joshua Fry Bullitt,” <em>Find A Grave</em>, May 9, 2010, memorial no. 52166895.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
