<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000811">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Streshly Jackson</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>James N. McAllister</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>James N. McAllister</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000811">
                    <persName>
                      James Streshly Jackson
                        (Representative)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1823-09-27"></birth>
                      <death when="1862-10-08"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney, soldier, and politician. Educated at Centre College and graduated from Jefferson College in 1844, and again from Transylvania University in 1845 with a law degree and admitted to the bar. Practiced law in Greenupsburg, Kentucky and Hopkinsville, Kentucky. Married to Martha Buford Jackson. Father of David Jackson, James Berryman Jackson, Etta Jackson, and Juliet Jackson. Served as a private and third lieutenant with the First Kentucky Cavalry in Mexican-American War. Resigned on October 10, 1846, fearing a court martial as the result of a duel he participated in. In 1859 he moved to Hopkinsville, and was elected to the U.S. Congress on March 4, 1861 in the Second Congressional District of Kentucky as Unionist member of the United States House of Representative. Resigned that position on December 13, 1861, to enter the Union Army. Raised a cavalry company which became the 3rd Kentucky Cavalry on December 13, 1861. Promoted to general on July 16, 1862.  Killed at the Battle of Perryville on October 8, 1862.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Allen, William B. <em>A History of Kentucky, embracing Gleanings, Reminiscences, Antiquities, Natural Curiosities, Statistics, and Biographical Sketches of Pioneers, Soldiers, Jurists, Lawywers, Statesmen, Divines, Mechanics, Farmers, Merchants, and other leading men, of all occupations and pursuits. Louisville, KY</em>.: Bradley &amp; Gilbert, Publishers, 1872.<br>
 <em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Jackson, James Streshly,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=J000019) (accessed December 2, 2016); Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, Town of Hopkinsville, p. 35-36; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Greenup County, District No 2.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
