<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003145">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Brooks Fairleigh</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003145">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas Brooks Fairleigh
                        (Colonel 26th Kentucky Veteran Infantry and )
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1837-01-27"></birth>
                      <death when="1890-11-02"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky lawyer and soldier. Lived in Brandenburg, Kentucky in 1860. Graduated from University of Louisville Law School in 1858. Returned to Brandenburg to practice law. Served as a captain in the 26th Kentucky Infantry from February 1862 to May 1862. Served as major from May 1862 to June 1862. Served as lieutenant colonel from June 1862 to August 1862. Served as AAG on the staff of General Stephen G. Burbridge and General Horatio P. Van Cleave from August 1862 to November 1862. Served as Bowling Green post commander from August 1863 to January 1864. Served on the staff of General Burbridge from March 1864 to May 1864. Served as Louisville post commander May 1864 to January 1865. Served as colonel of the 26th Kentucky Veteran Infantry from January 1865 to July 1865. Relocated to Louisville to practice law in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Roger D. Hunt, <em>Colonels in BlueIndiana—Kentucky and Tennessee: A Civil War Biographical Dictionary</em> (Jefferson, NC: McFarland &amp; Company, Inc., 2014), 155; &quot;Col. Fairleigh Dead,&quot; <em>Courier-Journal</em> (Louisville, Ky.), November 3, 1890; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Meade County, Brandenburg, p. 11.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
