<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007466">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Rodophil E. Jeter</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007466">
                    <persName>
                      Rodophil E. Jeter
                        (Provost Marshal of Campbellsville, Taylor County)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1821-11-30"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Residence: Campbellsville, Taylor County, KY. A Kentucky-born house joiner. Son of Anderson Jeter and Sorrow S. Allen. Married Sarah A. (aka Martha A.?) Provost Marshal of Campbellsville during the Civil War. Captain of Company C, 13th KY Volunteer Infantry. Mustered in 31 Dec 1861, Camp Hobson, KY. Mustered out 19 Apr 1862. Resigned. Father of John J. Jeter.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensberg, p. 91.</p>

<p>Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Taylor County, Campbellsville, p. 5.</p>

<p>William Henry Perrin, J.H. Battle, G.C. Kniffin, <em>Sketches From Adair, Boyle, Casey, Cumberland, Garrard, Green, Lincoln, Madison, Marion, Mercer, Nelson, Taylor, Washington Counties</em> (Genealogical Reference Company, 1970). (Accessed https://books.google.com/booksid=NPwTAAAAYAAJ&amp;dq=%22sketches+from+adair%2C+boyle%22&amp;focus=searchwithinvolume&amp;q=Jeter)</p>

<p><em>Report of the Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky</em>, vol. 1, 1861-1866 (Frankfort: Kentucky Yeoman Office, 1866), 859.</p>

<p>Steven L. Wright, <em>Kentucky Soldiers and Their Regiments in the Civil War: Abstracted From the Pages of Contemporary Newspapers, Volumes 4-5</em>, (Lois N. Miller Genealogical Publications, 2009). (Accessed https://books.google.com/books?id=oYEdAQAAMAAJ&amp;dq=%22Kentucky+soldiers+and+their+regiments+in+the+civil+war%22&amp;focus=searchwithinvolume&amp;q=Jeter)</p>

<p>&quot;[John J] Jeter, the Slayer of an Indianapolis Policeman, Proves to be a Thoroughly Bad Man,&quot; Chicago <em>Daily Tribune</em>, 30 Aug 1882, 2. ProQuest Historical Newspapers.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
