<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000857">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John J. Thomas</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000857">
                    <persName>
                      John J. Thomas
                        (Provisional Congress of the Confederate States)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1813-08-08"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky farmer, soldier, and politician. Worked as a surveyor and farmer in Christian County, Kentucky. Worked as a clerk in the United States Post Office in Washington, D.C. during the James K. Polk administration. Married to Kate Thomas. Father of Lewis M. Thomas, John Q. Thomas, Pendleton Thomas, and Annie Thomas. Owned fifty enslaved persons in 1860. Served as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1851 to 1853. Returned to farming in Christian County from 1853 to 1861. Served as a member of the Provisional Congress of the Confederate States from 1861 to 1862. Served as an aide to General John “Cerro Gordo” S. Williams in the Army of the Confederate States from 1862 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Ezra J. Warner and W. Buck Yearns, <em>Biographical Register of the Confederate Congress</em> (Baton Rouge: Louisiana State University Press, 1975), 235-236; Lewis Collins and Richard Collins, <em>History of Kentucky</em>, vol. 1 (Collins &amp; Company, 1882), 353; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, District No 2; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, p. 100; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, p. 73; Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, 11th Civil District, p. 6.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
