<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002941">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Denton Geoghegan</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002941">
                    <persName>
                      Denton Geoghegan
                        (Hardin County physician and farmer)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1824-04-23"></birth>
                      <death when="1869-11-16"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky physician and farmer. Lived in Hardin County, Kentucky in 1860. Owned two enslaved persons in 1860 and lived in his mother&#39;s household owning an additional seven enslaved persons. Member of the Episcopal Church. Worked on father&#39;s farmer until 1842. Worked as brick-mason in Mississippi from 1842 to 1844. Returned to Elizabethtown, Kentucky to study medicine under one of his brothers, Dr. Thomas D. Geoghegan. Graduated from the Louisville Medical College in 1846. Practiced medicine in West Point, Kentucky from 1846 to 1854. Returned to Elizabethtown and practiced medicine from 1854 until his death in 1869.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Samuel Haycraft, <em>A History of Elizabethtown, Kentucky, and its Surroundings</em> (Elizabethtown, Ky.: The Woman&#39;s Club of Elizabethtown, Ky., 1921 ), 129; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hardin County, District No. 1, p. 90; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hardin County, Elizabethtown Dist No. 1, p. 9.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
