<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000264">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">James Calvin McFerran</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000264">
                    <persName>
                      James Calvin McFerran
                        (of McFerran &amp; Menefee)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1812"></birth>
                      <death when="1885"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Born in Glasgow, Kentucky, in 1812. Married Margaret A. Rogers c. 1834. Father of J. B. McFerran. Hotel Keeper in Munfordville, Bowling Green, and Camelion Springs, Kentucky. Stock breeder in Bowling Green. Owned a livery and sale stable in Nashville, Tennessee in 1860. Owned McFerran &amp; Menefee, commission merchants and cotton factors, in partnewship with J. B. McFerran and Richard J. Menefee.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>&quot;A Busy Life Close,&quot; Louisville Courier-Journal, 10/26/1885. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Warren County, District 2, stamped p. 103. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Davidson County, Nashville Ward 2, p. 53. J. D. Campbell’s Louisville Business Directory for 1864 (Louisville: L. A. Civill, 1864), 189., Edward, Greenough, and DeVed, eds., Edwards’ Annual Director to the Inhabitants, Incorporated Companies, Manufacturing Establishments, Business Firms, Etc., Etc. in the City of Louisville, for 1865-6 (Louisville: Edward, Greenough, &amp; DeVed, 1866), 421.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
