<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000818">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Greenfield &quot;Green&quot; Adams</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000818">
                    <persName>
                      Greenfield &quot;Green&quot; Adams
                        (Representative)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1812-08-20"></birth>
                      <death when="1884-01-18"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney and politician. Studied law and admitted to the bar. Practiced law in Barbourville, Kentucky. Member of the Whig Party. Married twice, first to Mary Adams and a second time to Josephine Adams. Father of Alexander H. Adams, Thomas Randolf Adams, Amelia Adams, Eliza S. Adams, John S. Adams, and Henry Clay Adams. Served as deputy sheriff in Knox County, Kentucky from 1832 to 1833. Elected as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives from 1839 to 1842. Served as a presidential elector to the 1844 Whig Party ticket. Served the Sixth Congressional District of Kentucky as a Whig Party member of the United States House of Representative from 1847 to 1849 and as a Democratic Party member from 1859 to 1861. Served as judge of the Knox County Circuit Court from 1851 to 1856. Appointed and served as auditor of the United States Treasury Department  from 1861 to 1864. Practiced law with John W. Stokes in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Adams, Green,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=A000036) (accessed December 14, 2016); Charles Lanman, <em>Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States</em> (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 2; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Knox County; Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Pennsylvania, Philadelphia County, 44 Disct 15th Ward Phil. City, p. 53; “Greenfield Adams,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=12860) (accessed December 14, 2016).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
