<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000881">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Leslie Combs</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000881">
                    <persName>
                      Leslie Combs
                        (Clerk of the Court of Appeals)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1793-11-29"></birth>
                      <death when="1861-08-22"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Kentucky soldier, attorney, politician, and public servant. Educated by the Reverend John Lysle. Served as deputy clerk of the Clerk of the Courts of Jessamine County. Served as a cadet in the First Regiment of Kentucky Volunteers under General James Winchester and in various capacities under General William Henry Harrison, General Green Clay. Completed education in 1816 and read law with Samuel Q. Richardson in Lexington, Kentucky. Admitted to the bar in 1818 and practiced law in Lexington, Kentucky. Married twice, first to Margaret Trotter Combs and following her death to Mary Elizabeth Brownell Combs. Father of fourteen children. Member of the Whig Party. Raised a regiment in response to the Texas Revolution in 1836. Served in the Kentucky House of Representatives for several periods: 1827-1829, 1833, 1845-1847, and 1857-1859. Served as a delegate to the 1840 Whig Party Convention, supporting the nomination of Henry Clay. Canvassed for William Henry Harrison in the 1840 Presidential Election. Unsuccessful candidate for the United States House of Representatives against John C. Breckinridge in 1851. Served as clerk of the Court of Appeals of Kentucky from 1860 to 1866.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</em>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 79-80; Lewis Collins, <em>Collins’ Historical Sketches of Kentucky: History of Kentucky</em>, vol. 2 (Collins &amp; Company, 1878), 170; “Gen. Leslie Combs,” (https://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=8875416) (accessed February 9, 2017); Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, 4th Ward City of Lexington, p. 102.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
