<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000827">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Samuel McKee</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000827">
                    <persName>
                      Samuel McKee
                        (Representative)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1833-11-05"></birth>
                      <death when="1898-12-11"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney, soldier, and politician. Graduated from Miami University (Oxford, Ohio)  in 1857 and from the Cincinnati Law School in 1858.  Admitted to the bar and practiced law in Mount Sterling, Kentucky. Married to Sophia Brainerd McKee. Father of Frank McKee, Samuel McKee, Eugenia McKee Nettelroth, and Brainerd McKee. Served in the Civil War as a captain in the Fourteenth Kentucky Volunteer Cavalry from 1862 to 1864. A prisoner of war for 13 months at Libby Prison. Served the Ninth Congressional District of Kentucky as an Unconditional Unionist member of the United States House of Representative from 1865 to 1867.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “McKee, Samuel,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=M000497) (accessed January 5, 2017); Charles Lanman, <em>Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States</em> (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 334; “Samuel McKee,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=7095889) (accessed January 5, 2017); Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Montgomery County, Mount Sterling, p. 119; Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, 7 Ward City Louisville, p. 125-126.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
