<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN001760">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Abraham Lincoln</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N001760">
                    <persName>
                      Abraham Lincoln
                        (Railsplitter)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1809-02-12"></birth>
                      <death when="1865-04-15"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hardin County, Kentucky, native. Sixteenth president of the United States. Member of the Whig, Republican, and National Union Parties. Married Mary Ann Todd in 1842. Father of Robert Todd Lincoln, Edward Baker Lincoln, William Wallace Lincoln, and Thomas “Tad” Lincoln. No formal education. Served as a private and captain in the Illinois Militia during the Black Hawk War. Served as postmaster and county surveyor of New Salem, Illinois. Practiced law with John T. Stuart, Stephen T. Logan, and William Herndon in Illinois. Represented Sangamon County, Illinois in the House of Representatives of the State of Illinois from 1834 to 1842. Represented the 7th District of Illinois in the United States House of Representatives from 1847 to 1849. Elected president of the United States on November 6, 1860 and re-elected on November 8, 1864. Assassinated on April 14, 1865 at Ford’s Theatre in Washington, D. C., by John Wilkes Booth. Interred in Oak Ridge Cemetery in Springfield, Illinois.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>The Papers of Abraham Lincoln, s.v. “Abraham Lincoln Chronology,” http://www.papersofabrahamlincoln.org/resources/abraham-lincoln-chronology (accessed October 24, 2016); Michael Burlingame, Abraham Lincoln: A Life (Baltimore: Johns Hopkins University Press, 2008); David Herbert Donald, Lincoln (New York: Simon &amp; Schuster, 1996); Ronald C. White, Jr., A. Lincoln: A Biography (New York: Random House, Inc., 2009).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
