<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DO00000732">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Department of Kentucky</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

        <encodingDesc>
            <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
                <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
                </prefixDef>
            </listPrefixDef>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term type="type">Organization</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc>
                <org xml:id="O00000732">
                    <orgName>Department of Kentucky</orgName>
                </org>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>This department existed in two separate periods. The first was created on May 28, 1861. It was geographically defined as all Kentucky lands within 100 miles of the Ohio River. The department combined with the Department of the Cumberland on August 15, 1861. <em>Commander(s)</em>: Robert Anderson.</p>

<p>The second was created on February 10, 1865. It was geographically defined as the entire state of Kentucky, until March 24, 1865, when Jeffersonville and New Albany, Indiana were added to the department. It was assigned to the Military Division of Tennessee on June 27, 1865. The department combined with the Department of the Cumberland on June 5, 1866. <em>Commander(s)</em>:  John M. Palmer and Edward H. Hobson.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Frank J. Welcher, <em>The Union Army, 1861—1865: Organization and Operations, vol. 2, The Western Theatre</em> (Bloomington: Indiana University Press, 1993), 76-77.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
