<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DO00008223">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main"> Northern Bank of Kentucky. Glasgow Branch</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

        <encodingDesc>
            <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
                <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
                </prefixDef>
            </listPrefixDef>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term type="type">Organization</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc>
                <org xml:id="O00008223">
                    <orgName> Northern Bank of Kentucky. Glasgow Branch</orgName>
                      <event type="begun" when="1859-06-01">1859-06-01</event>
                      <event type="ended" when="c1876">c1876</event>
                </org>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Glasgow, Kentucky branch of the Northern Bank of Kentucky. Chartered by the Kentucky legislature, June 1, 1859. Thomas C. Dickinson appointed a Director in the Glasgow Branch of the Northern Bank of Kentucky upon its establishment and held the position until the branch was discontinued in c1876.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>The Biographical Encyclopaedia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</em> (Cincinnati, OH: J.M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 390-91.</p>

<p>Stanton, Richard H., <em>The Revised Statutes of Kentucky, Approved and Adopted by the General Assembly, 1851 and 1852, and in Force From July 1, 1852; with all the Amendments Subsequently Enacted. Volume II</em> (Cincinnati, OH: Robert Clarke &amp; Co, 1867), 500.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
