<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DO00000743">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Army of the James</title>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

        <encodingDesc>
            <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
                <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
                </prefixDef>
            </listPrefixDef>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term type="type">Organization</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc>
                <org xml:id="O00000743">
                    <orgName>Army of the James</orgName>
                      <event type="begun" when="1864-04-02">1864-04-02</event>
                      <event type="ended" when="1865-08-01">1865-08-01</event>
                </org>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>This Army was created on April 2, 1864. It consisted of the Tenth Corps and Eighteenth Corps. The Army was reorganized on June 18, 1864, each corps having three divisions.  On December 3, 1864, the Secreatary of War—upon request from Grant and Butler—ordered the reorganization the Army of the James into two new corps, the newly created Twenty-fourth Corps composed of the all white old Tenth and Eighteenth Crops and the newly create Twenty-fifth Corps composed of the African American troops of the Departments of Virginia and North Carolina.  By August 1, 1865, the Army of the James had been disbanded and reassigned. <em>Commander(s)</em>: William F. Smith, Benjamin F. Butler, Edward O. C. Ord, David B. Birney, Benjamin F. Butler, Godfrey Weitzel, and Alfred H. Terry.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Frank J. Welcher, <em>The Union Army, 1861—1865: Organization and Operations, vol. 1, The Eastern Theatre</em> (Bloomington: Indiana University Press, 1989), 218-241.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
