<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DO00000739">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Northern Department</title>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

        <encodingDesc>
            <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
                <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
                </prefixDef>
            </listPrefixDef>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term type="type">Organization</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc>
                <org xml:id="O00000739">
                    <orgName>Northern Department</orgName>
                      <event type="begun" when="1864-01-12">1864-01-12</event>
                      <event type="ended" when="1865-06-27">1865-06-27</event>
                </org>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>This department was created on January 12, 1864. It was geographically defined by the states of Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, and Ohio. Jeffersonville, Indiana and Cairo Illinois transferred out of the department on February 8, 1864. Alton, Illinois transferred out of the department on February 15, 1864. Covington, Kentucky and those Kentucky lands within a ten mile radius were added to the department on June 25, 1864, until it was transferred to the Department of Kentucky on February 10, 1865. Jeffersonville, Indiana rejoined the department on February 10, 1865, until it was transferred along with New Albany, Indiana to the Department of Kentucky on March 24, 1865. Cairo, Illinois once again joined the department on November 28, 1864. The Northern Department was disbanded on June 27, 1865 when it merged with the Department of the Ohio. <em>Commander(s)</em>: Samuel P. Heintzelman and Joseph Hooker.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Frank J. Welcher, <em>The Union Army, 1861—1865: Organization and Operations, vol. 2, The Western Theatre</em> (Bloomington: Indiana University Press, 1993), 120-122.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
