<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DO00007040">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">USS Lexington</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Tyler Campbell</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

        <encodingDesc>
            <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
                <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
                </prefixDef>
            </listPrefixDef>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term type="type">Organization</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc>
                <org xml:id="O00007040">
                    <orgName>USS Lexington</orgName>
                      <event type="begun" when="1861">1861</event>
                      <event type="ended" when="1865">1865</event>
                </org>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Commissioned and built at Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania in 1861. The USS Lexington III was the third USS Lexington in the United States Navy. It was a sidewheel steamer. During the Civil War, the ship seized steamer W. B. Terry at Paducah, Kentucky, participated in the  attack on Paducah,  the Battle of Belmont, the Battle of Fort Henry, the Battle of Shiloh, the Battle of Saint Charles, and the Battle of Milliken&#39;s Bend. It also saw action in numerous encounters on the Ohio and Mississippi Rivers. The USS Lexington was decommissioned July 2, 1865 at Mound City, Illinois. There it was sold to Thomas Scott and Wooodburn on August 17, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Naval History and Heritage Command,</em> &quot;Lexington III (sidewheel steamer) 1861-1865,&quot;  accessed June 13, 2017, https://www.history.navy.mil/research/histories/ship-histories/danfs/l/lexington-sidewheel-steamer-iii.html.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
