<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DP00008235">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Quincy, Illinois</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Jesse Nasta</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

        <encodingDesc>
            <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
                <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
                </prefixDef>
            </listPrefixDef>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term type="type">Place</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc>
                <place xml:id="P00008235">
                    <placeName>
                        <location>
                            <settlement>Quincy, Illinois</settlement>
                        </location>
                    </placeName>
                </place> 
            </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Locate on the Mississippi River, about 20 miles north of Hannibal, Missouri. Quincy&#39;s founder, John Wood, settled there in 1812. Town named in 1825. Designated the county seat of Adams County, Illinois in 1825. Quincy Land office established in the mid-1830s. During the winter of 1838-1839, five thousand member of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Days Saints were driven from their homes in Missouri and arrived in Quincy, where they found temporary shelter on their way to Nauvoo. Beginning in the 1840s, Quincy was a center of underground railroad activity. By the 1850s, Quincy had become Illinois&#39;s third largest city, and, in 1853, Congress designated Quincy a port of entry for foreign goods. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>&quot;Quincy History,&quot; http://genealogytrails.com/ill/adams/history/quincyhistory.html</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>